<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
<channel>
  <title>Vecderg Github RSS Feed</title>
  <description>Updates on my posts</description>
  <link>https://vecderg.github.io/</link>
  <lastBuildDate>
    Thu, Sep 26 2024 08:09:43 +0000
  </lastBuildDate>
<!-- TEMPLATE // https://www.unixtimestamp.com/
  <item>
    <title>Insert Title</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
		<p class="normal">
		
		</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/</link>
    <pubDate>
      Wed, Sep 18 2024 20:23:34 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>
-->
  
  <item>
    <title>Conlangs and My Language Journey</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
		<p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
		September 25, 2024 - Published 
		</p>

		<p class="normal">
		One of my mutuals from Cohost recently reached out to me about Globasa, and hey! You're super cool! 
		But it also reminded me that my language journey has been really confusing and worth writing down 
		somewhere. 
		<br />
		<br />
		While I'm not someone unable to make commitments on important things, I'm notoriously fickle 
		when it comes to my hobbies if I'm not lucky enough to hyperfocus on something, so it's understandable. 
		On a more personal note, yes I'm very aware this is like a glaring sign of neurodivergence, 
		and we're still figuring that out.
		<br />
		<br />
		Anyway, my point is: days after I posted 
		<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4pMDnqRRAaM" target="_blank">my Globasa video</a>, 
		I had basically stopped doing anything Globasa. No more interest in studying the grammar, the vocab; 
		no interest in speaking it with people or convincing anyone to learn it. 
		<br />
		<br />
		I was very invested in Globasa's growth, but I lost the energy to partake in it. The same thing happened after I posted the Mini-Linga video. The same thing happened before I even finished the last Ido video. 
		<br />
		<br />
		I did enjoy my time a lot! I just generally have a limited timespan that I'm interested in a particular 
		subject. To be frank, my interest in conlangs has far exceeded this average timespan, possibly because 
		there are so many to choose from. 
		<br />
		<br />
		Since I've essentially only talked about this stuff in-depth on Cohost, I wanted to talk about my WHOLE 
		language journey, largely for my own satisfaction. However, I'll put the most important things upfront first
		for those less interested in me doing a full infodump.
		<br />
		<br />
		--WHAT'S HAPPENING NOW--
		<br />
		<br />
		At this specific second, I'm only committed to 2 languages. I'm committed to learning Japanese, and I'm 
		committed to finishing Dasopya, my conlang. I'm interested in a lot more languages, but these 2 languages alone
		have put enough on my plate that I can't take on much more in good conscience. I'll talk more about Japanese
		later on, but Dasopya is essentially my third attempt at creating an auxiliary language for the whole world to use. 
		<br />
		<br />
		If I include work that's been carried over from the last language, I've been working on this language for 
		almost 3 months straight, so support is much appreciated! You can find the main website 
		<a href="https://www.dasopya.com/" target="_blank">here</a>, which has all the links along with exclusive material.
		<br />
		<br />
		I've done multiple small translations in the language and multiple overviews, but note that the language 
		is still only about 80% finished so there still may be minor changes to the existing vocabulary. I'm 
		aiming for about 800 root words, currently hovering a bit over 700. The grammar is basically 95% complete, 
		where only edge cases are really a cause for concern.
		<br />
		<br />
		If you haven't seen it, Dasopya is a language made to be simple and consistent, with every root word being 2
		syllables or less. Each word is based on sound symbolism and existing languages to sound familiar, but 
		are made unrecognizable to avoid favoring speakers of any region, unlike most auxlangs. Despite the relatively 
		small vocabulary, the grammar and compounding rules allow speakers to express anything they need to.
		<br />
		<br />
		pumi: i songabi tehi sili e legigen!
		<br />
		<br />
		--HOW IT STARTED--
		<br />
		<br />
		It might be a little excessive to talk about this much, but it does give some context for later.
		<br />
		<br />
		In the U.S., most (all?) students are required to take a few years of foreign language. I knew Spanish would be
		the easy choice, but French was a lot more interesting to me. Frankly, this was probably just because Spanish
		would be the common choice for most of my classmates, and I like being an annoying contrarian.
		<br />
		<br />
		Unfortunately, I regretted it pretty quickly because pretty much nothing clicked. This could be for many
		reasons (I vaguely remember not taking the class very seriously), but it's also a not-so-secret fact that
		second language classes in the U.S. aren't super successful. 
		<br />
		<br />
		I distinctly remember struggling with accent marks since I never felt they were explained to me properly (and 
		there's like 4!), so I had to search them up on my own, only to more confusion. While I was lucky enough to 
		enjoy the teacher and the general environment, there was very little I took away from the class by the end of 
		the year, and I switched to Spanish the next year.
		<br />
		<br />
		I remember very little from Spanish class. It felt a lot more like school. Memorize these things, repeat them
		back, do the homework where you repeat it again, then come to class where you get tested on it. 
		<br />
		<br />
		French class may have been where I ate my first croissant and had an (unfulfilled) promise of a cool class 
		trip to France, but Spanish class was entirely fulfilling a requirement. After finishing Spanish class, I had 
		essentially no interest in these languages again.
		<br />
		<br />
		--WHERE IT WENT--
		<br />
		<br />
		From here, most USAmericans never seriously pick up a language again from the statistics I can understand, and
		I don't think that's much of a surprise! School is an easy way to kill enthusiasm in an otherwise interesting
		subject.
		<br />
		<br />
		But for whatever reason, something possessed me to pick up Japanese about a year later, for reasons I won't 
		bother looking for. I've always been a fan of Japanese media, and later most of the culture too, but everyone 
		knew it was a very difficult language to learn. 
		<br />
		<br />
		Either way, about a month later, I gave up not due to the difficulty itself, but because the lack of any 
		speakers to bounce off made it very difficult to practice or keep up motivation.
		<br />
		<br />
		A few years later, having a French-speaking friend, I guess something in me really wanted to pick up
		language studies again, because it still felt like a bit of a whim. I tried French again in a decently valiant 
		attempt -- it lasted over a year, even if on and off -- but I burned out yet again. 
		<br />
		<br />
		This was due to a variety of reasons, but a big sentiment by the end was just frustration. I got very tired of 
		the lack of consistency and constant exceptions. This is the ONLY place I will ever officially say this, but
		this is the ACTUAL reason I began work on Kalibe, later known as Kaliwe. I got annoyed at French!
		<br />
		<br />
		--THE CONLANG ARC--
		<br />
		<br />
		Kaliwe was actually an idea in my head for a long time, from multiple points of inspiration. I found English to
		rather inefficient where many words meant the same thing, and many words could just be derived from existing 
		words by putting them together. I wanted to boil down language to a tiny, simple set of words that could be put
		together in any way you want.
		<br />
		<br />
		Now, I never deluded myself into thinking this was a never-before-done concept, but it's actually only recently
		that I ever found out the actual term for this type of language. Yes, Kaliwe is an a priori oligosynthetic
		auxlang, but the actual logic behind its creation aligns more perfectly with the classification of being a 
		<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Philosophical_language" target="_blank">philosophical language</a>,
		less in the lines of Toki Pona as an example given by Wikipedia, and more in line with a language like 
		<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ro_language" target="_blank">Ro</a>.
		<br />
		<br />
		And if you read the article on Ro, you'll know that philosophical languages never took off, because they just
		dooon't really work in practice! 
		<br />
		<br />
		Anyway, during the creation of Kaliwe, I was talking with a friend who brought up Toki Pona because it was the
		closest equivalent they knew, being a minimalistic conlang. At first I was uninterested, then I realized that
		being rather out of my depth, more points of reference would be helpful. 
		<br />
		<br />
		Eventually, I finished the language and post it online, to a surprising amount of attention. It's not huge, but
		I got many comments. Despite this, I still had no idea what to do WITH the language, other than possibly sneak
		bits of it into my work. Around the same day, I note, "I may learn Toki Pona sometime for similarly nefarious
		purposes." 
		<br />
		<br />
		Huh! Not the reason I expected when I went back to search.
		<br />
		<br />
		--BACK TO LANGUAGE LEARNING--
		<br />
		<br />
		I assume my close proximity with Toki Pona (I'm just gonna keep capitalizing it because I feel like it) was the
		main reason I decided to "bite the bullet" -- I had already learned half the concepts for research purposes, so
		I might as well learn the rest.
		<br />
		<br />
		There were some language-related things that happened during this time (I poked at learning my family's native 
		language, though I'm not sure when I'm spilling what that is), but for the most part, it was just me and my 
		friend learning bits of Toki Pona for months. 
		<br />
		<br />
		I finally had another speaker I could bounce a second language off of! We had resources that were reliable, the
		language was simple, and I couldn't feel self-conscious about my speech, because I wasn't speaking to a native.
		<br />
		<br />
		It was a very good experience, but eventually I wanted more. After bouncing between different conlangs, I came
		to Esperanto.
		<br />
		<br />
		Esperanto was also very simple and easy to learn, but had way more words and angles of expression, so it would
		be more of a project. I spent about 1 month with more intense study than Toki Pona and felt very proud of 
		myself by the end, being able to understand almost 50% of every text I read in that short amount of time. I 
		would still have difficulties remembering words when speaking, but it was an unimaginably different experience 
		from my time with natural languages.
		<br />
		<br />
		By the end of the year, my motivation ran low yet again. A sudden piece of news dropped.
		<br />
		<br />
		--EUROPE--
		<br />
		<br />
		My parents invited me to a trip to Europe! This almost came out of nowhere, and we had to prepare in just a few
		months. As someone several feet deep into languages, I had to figure all that stuff out.
		<br />
		<br />
		After Esperanto, I had already been building up some affection again for the natural languages I had shaken 
		my fist at just less than a year prior, and now was the time to use what I learned. I spent the months to learn
		Italian and German, while giving myself a refresher on Spanish and French. 
		And <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XZi-ChciSIg" target="_blank">the trip went great!</a>
		<br />
		<br />
		(link is for a video on a mostly unrelated subject, but is the only public discussion I have on my trip to Europe)
		<br />
		<br />
		However, after all that I really wanted to settle down and learn a language. For over a year now, I've been 
		The Language Guy to both my friends and family, and more than that, I wanted to prove to myself that I could
		make the commitment to learn a language all the way through.
		<br />
		<br />
		No more auxlangs, no more giving up 1 month in, no more indecision. Let's learn a language!
		<br />
		<br />
		--TO THE PRESENT--
		<br />
		<br />
		Wow, OK this one is getting long. This is the last section, I promise.
		<br />
		<br />
		I chose Spanish, and it fell apart in about a month. It was the "correct" choice, the easy one, the one that I 
		should be able to learn. And, well, I did! I'm not amazing at Spanish, but my goal was be conversational, and
		between my years of schooling, study before the trip, and study after the trip, I was indeed conversational to 
		a very basic degree that could be used with other Spanish speakers, if they spoke slowly enough.
		<br />
		<br />
		But I just couldn't find that secret sauce, the motivation to learn the language that ran deeper than
		"because it's easy and useful." So after everything, I chose Japanese.
		<br />
		<br />
		The majority of my favorite non-USAmerican media is Japanese, I love their food, aesthetics, culture, and
		yes, I do like anime and manga. Call me a weeb if you want! I will only be slightly offended. 
		<br />
		<br />
		My motivation has waned a few times, but we're almost 5 months into Japanese learning, and I think that's a
		great achievement already. After so much time with European languages too, it felt nice to sink my teeth into
		something that was much more foreign, with grammar rules that would take a lot more time for me to learn.
		<br />
		<br />
		However, there was something bothering me in the back of my head. Japanese, it 
		reminded me a lot of conlangs, the way certain words were constructed. Kind of like Kaliwe...
		<br />
		<br />
		I was never fully satisfied with Kaliwe. That's why it's called Kaliwe now, is because I updated Kalibe,
		but I still wasn't happy with this updated version. No, I couldn't make another conlang, it was a bad
		idea!
		<br />
		<br />
		...in a feverish rush around 2AM, I wrote a quick outline document. The next day, I almost worked 13 hours
		straight on Taynmoga.
		<br />
		<br />
		--I LIED--
		<br />
		<br />
		I'm not sure how many people know what it's like to work on something for so long, a hobbyist project,
		without WANTING to. I was essentially compelled by an invisible force. I had to create this. I don't know
		why. Sometimes I feel something similar with art, but this was so much more intense.
		<br />
		<br />
		I work on it for over a week, multiple hours a day for most days. The language has just under 450 words. 
		Another 2 weeks: it breaks 450 words, has a 15 page document, a beginner's guide with 10 lessons. I publish it.
		<br />
		<br />
		Response seems restrained. Then, it's announced that a channel has been added to the Auxlang Discord for it.
		<br />
		<br />
		Oh, fudge.
		<br />
		<br />
		It takes me a while to decide what to do with a language I never really wanted to create? But, eventually I 
		decide that the only thing that made sense was to turn it into something I wanted to support. Abandoning it 
		would feel like my month was wasted, and promoting Taynmoga would feel disingenuous. 
		<br />
		<br />
		And so I made Dasopya. 
		<br />
		<br />
		It has some compromises that make it a bit less "neat" from my ideal concept, but in favor of it being a lot 
		more practical, so I'm happy with it for now. I'm really not sure where it'll go, but I hope it grants me that
		inner peace I've always wanted from creating a conlang I'm satisfied with. 
		<br />
		<br />
		--CONCLUSION--
		<br />
		<br />
		So yeah, basically I learned French, then Spanish, then Japanese, then French again, then made Kaliwe, then
		learned Toki Pona, then had a huge conlang spree where I eventually learned Esperanto, then I learned Spanish
		again, then Italian, then German, then French again, then Spanish again, then Japanese, then I made Taynmoga,
		then I made Dasopya.
		<br />
		<br />
		Make sense? Awesome. I had to skip a few parts.
		<br />
		<br />
		<br />
		<br />
		</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts4.html</link>
    <pubDate>
      Thu, Sep 26 2024 08:09:43 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>
  
 <item>
    <title>On DracoFighter 2</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
		<p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
		September 17, 2024 - Published 
		</p>
      <p class="normal">
		<b>SUMMARY: DracoFighter 2 is in development, has no engine yet but 7/8 of characters have fully designed movesets with 5.5/8 fully sprited. Everything else is still in planning stages.</b>
		<br />
		<br />
		Like a DUMMY I forgot to give an update on my most major project in my last post, but that's 
		OK because this probably deserves its own post anyway. Since this is the only real mention 
		of DracoFighter 2 on this site so far, I'm going to summarize everything from DracoFighter 1 
		to bring everyone up to speed.
		<br />
		<br />
		--ABOUT DRACOFIGHTER 1--
		<br />
		<br />
		DracoFighter is a game I launched on 
		<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2027810/DracoFighter" target="_blank">Steam</a> 
		(and Itch and Google Play Store) marketed as a fighting game for beginners. It's also my 
		dream project, my biggest solo project (game or otherwise), and many other things that I 
		could spend 3 whole articles talking about. 
		<br />
		<br />
		But essentially, it's a 2D fighter meant to <b>bare down the genre to the most essential parts</b>, 
		without resorting to something gimmicky (like Divekick) or dry (like Footsies). Nothing 
		against those games since they deliver perfectly on what they were going for, but they didn't 
		deliver the experience that <i>I</i> was looking for, which was a fully-fledged fighting game 
		that <i>felt</i> like a traditional fighting game, fully playable on mobile devices.
		<br />
		<br />
		DracoFighter is a finished game, but it missed the mark in some areas. It didn't have inputs 
		for up/down to make mobile inputs simpler, but that made jumping/blocking unintuitive for 
		many players. It also had no online play, which killed the possibility of any real widespread 
		playerbase. Since rollback is a necessity nowadays, I would have to rebuild the game in an 
		entirely new engine to make it compatible with rollback. So... why not just do that for a new game?
		<br />
		<br />
		--DRACOFIGHTER 2--
		<br />
		<br />
		Many people were surprised that I was so quick to start a DracoFighter 2, but to be honest, 
		I wanted DracoFighter 2 before Dracofighter 1 even began development. That's because internally, 
		I actually referred to the first game as DracoFighter Zero -- the PREQUEL to the actual game.
		<br />
		<br />
		The original idea for the game had Draco travel to the past with other dragons to fight against 
		the dinosaurs, for reasons I was still developing. However, making my first fighting game have 
		like 8 different characters was very much outside a reasonable scope, so I downsized the cast to 
		4 and wrote the story to happen as an explanation for why he went back in time. This very much 
		worked out in my favor!  
		<br />
		<br />
		DracoFighter 2 is the fully-fledged sequel to DracoFighter 1, planned to have a base cast of 8 characters, longer story, more singleplayer content, and online play with rollback netcode. To make it possible, I'm reusing knowledge/assets from the first game and building on it to feel more like a fully-featured fighting game while still being aimed towards beginners (though I may leave that out of the marketing this time -- I don't think people like buying games that call them a beginner lol).
		<br />
		<br />
		I'm still keeping some features under wraps for announcements later on, but I've mentioned that: 1) there are now only 2 attack buttons (Attack/Special) and 4 directions (U/D/L/R), 2) game mechanics are 90% the same, but a super armor mechanic is being added + jumps are universal and beat grabs, 3) mirroring the 8 base characters, there are 8 secret characters planned, which may be added as free DLC rather than base-game depending on how development goes.
		<br />
		<br />
		HOWEVER, there is a very big, very awkward issue here.<br />
		And that's that I'm spriting a game that doesn't have an engine!
		<br />
		<br />
		--THE ENGINE ISSUE--
		<br />
		<br />
		There is no fighting game engine currently on the market that 1) fits my needs and 2) is complete, so I've been working on what I can while waiting for these engines to be finished. There are a couple of options, but there is a chance that I might have to just make my own from scratch, which isn't ideal for a number of reasons. 
		<br />
		<br />
		We all know networking is hard, especially when you have 0 experience making an online game! But it also comes with other issues that aren't just about making it function -- how do I create a secure system that prevents hackers? If there's a serious bug in the engine, can I be relied upon to fix it? What if I work in Godot, which is an open source engine that can be easily decompiled? If there's a reporting system, who reviews them?
		<br />
		<br />
		Once online is introduced, especially with random players, there are a ton of practical issues where it becomes very unrealistic for a single person to manage everything, especially with no experience. Even the 20 person Discord server for DracoFighter got raided by people who thought it was funny to sling racial slurs, and I couldn't fix it in a timely manner because I was asleep and didn't think it was necessary to appoint any moderators for such a small server...
		<br />
		<br />
		Anyway, my point is that it works a lot better if I work on an engine made by other people who are more experienced that can be reached out to for help, though I may also have to figure out a way sometime to build a team, even if it introduces even more issues (where do I get the money to pay people a full wage!).
		<br />
		<br />
		--ACTUAL UPDATES--
		<br />
		<br />
		Currently, I've been modding new characters into the DracoFighter 1 engine just to test out sprites and movesets, which has been working very well. This build cannot be released due to how buggy it is, but has allowed me to advance a lot of the game despite not having a real engine to build off of. I may release this build as an exclusive thing for DF2 purchasers in the future if people are really interested? Either way, if you see footage of DracoFighter 2 at this point in time, it's probably in this frankenstein of an engine.
		<br />
		<br />
		Speaking of which, here is the first video I uploaded to Bluesky of DracoFighter 2 gameplay:
		<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecdev.bsky.social/post/3l3y6wkjzda2t" target="_blank">https://bsky.app/profile/vecdev.bsky.social/post/3l3y6wkjzda2t</a>
		<br />
		<br />
		As for the confirmed characters:<br />
		Draco, Plexie, BiOS, Cyrus - DracoFighter 1 characters
		<br />
		TREX, RAPTOR, STEGO, DILO - DracoFighter 2 newcomers
		<br />
		<br />
		(They are already named, just won't be announced yet &lt;3)
		<br />
		<br />
		Needs finished moveset design: Cyrus <br />
		Needs considerable number of sprites: RAPTOR (50% finished), DILO (5%), Cyrus (25%)
		<br />
		<br />
		I'm VERY happy with how the currently-finished characters play and animate, and I'm still very excited to show it to the wider world. The reason Cyrus is lagging behind is because unlike the other DracoFighter 1 characters, I've never been fully satisfied with how he played. I'm probably keeping his updates simple, but they still need implementation and testing.
		<br />
		<br />
		Either way, thank you very much for reading! If you want to follow DracoFighter, you can always follow my <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecdev.bsky.social/" target="_blank">Bluesky dev account</a>, 
		but I'll be continuing to note major updates here.
		<br />
		<br />
		</p>

    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts3.html</link>
    <pubDate>
      Wed, Sep 18 2024 20:37:29 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>On Cohost</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
      <p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
		September 12, 2024 - Published 
		</p>

		<p class="normal">
		With Cohost going down, it is essentially the second time I have to move my digital home elsewhere.
		This event is rather big for me, not due to the event alone (which is big, but the website only
		existed for about 2 years and was never colossal), but due to what it signifies for me as someone
		whose home is on the internet.
		<br />
		<br />
		I'm learning how RSS feeds work so this website can be somewhere I connect with more people,
		because it is now one of the few places I can properly express myself. I've written
		<a href="../articles/article1.html">my first article</a> on this website to fully vent out 
		my feelings on the situation, so note that it'll be more negative and dramatic than my usual
		content.
		<br />
		<br />
		Otherwise, the most notable updates are that 1) I'll be more active on BlueSky, where I created
		<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecdev.bsky.social" target="_blank">a new dev account</a> 
		(Vecdev) for anyone only interested in my gamedev endeavors. Of course, you can still
		find me on Bluesky under <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social" target="_blank">Vecderg</a> 
		for my general content.
		<br />
		<br />
		2) I've been making great progress on my conlang, <a href="https://www.dasopya.com/" target="_blank">Dasopya</a>!
		I briefly announced this on Cohost, but it's a language made for international communication where
		every word is made from scratch (a priori). I will be continuing to promote and update on it, so 
		expect that in the future -- it currently has over 700 words!
		<br />
		<br />
		The main website is fully laid out to introduce the language, but more interestingly, I also have a 
		converter + font for the alternate writing system! You can find both at this itch page:
		<a href="https://vecderg.itch.io/pyalibu" target="_blank">https://vecderg.itch.io/pyalibu</a>
		<br />
		<br />
		As always, thank you all for the support.
		</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts2.html</link>
    <pubDate>
      Wed, Sep 18 2024 20:36:29 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Archive</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
      <p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
		September 12, 2024 - Published 
		</p>

		<p class="normal">
		This is to archive all the old update posts before the RSS Feed was added. These links used to display on the front page,
		but some of them may become broken in the future.
		</p>

		<p class="normal">
		<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecdev.bsky.social/post/3l3txmtsuiv26" target="_blank">Announcement - New Dev Account! (Bluesky)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://itaku.ee/images/917362" target="_blank">Art - Gulusgammamon Choccy Milk (Itaku)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/7359441-dasopya-the-next-o" target="_blank">Conlang - Dasopya Announcement (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/7262692-sketch-dump" target="_blank">Art - Sketch Dump (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://itaku.ee/posts/139305" target="_blank">Art - Artfight Attacks 3 (Itaku)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://itaku.ee/posts/138038" target="_blank">Art - Artfight Attacks 2 (Itaku)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/6860304-my-new-450-word-lang" target="_blank">Conlang - Taynmoga Announcement (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://itaku.ee/posts/137603" target="_blank">Art - Artfight Attacks 1 (Itaku)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/artphototrad" target="_blank">Article - How to Take Photos of Traditional Art</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/6325949-sona-partment-24-5" target="_blank">Art - SonaPartment #24.5 (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://itaku.ee/images/844803" target="_blank">Art - Ube Sit, Traditional (Itaku)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/6290786-sona-partment-24" target="_blank">Art - SonaPartment #24 (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/6195460-empty" target="_blank">Art - That Dog in Me (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/6153768-sona-partment-23" target="_blank">Art - SonaPartment #23 (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/6069382-sona-partment-22" target="_blank">Art - SonaPartment #22 (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4pMDnqRRAaM" target="_blank">Video - Overview: Globasa Tutorial (Youtube)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/auxlangs3" target="_blank">Article - Thoughts on Auxlang Marketing</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/5986577-sona-partment-21" target="_blank">Art - SonaPartment #21 (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/5892473-sona-partment-20" target="_blank">Art - SonaPartment #20 (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/originalityoverrated" target="_blank">Article - Why Originality is Overrated</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XZi-ChciSIg" target="_blank">Video - 5 Reasons Why Conlangs are NOT Useless (Youtube)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://itaku.ee/images/812476" target="_blank">Art - Polaris Commission (Itaku)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mXBMia_KBkc" target="_blank">Video - Overview: Mini-Linga Tutorial (Youtube)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://itaku.ee/images/783219" target="_blank">Art - Smolder (Itaku)</a><br />
		<br /> 
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/4987553-i-did-the-cassette-t" target="_blank">Art - DracoFighter Casette (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/auxlangs2" target="_blank">Article - Why There Can't be a Perfect Auxlang</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://itaku.ee/images/766686" target="_blank">Art - Hyde Reference Sheet (Itaku)</a><br />
		<br /> 
		<a href="https://itaku.ee/images/753094" target="_blank">Art - Tea Party (Itaku)</a><br />
		<br /> 
		<a href="other.html">Game - Egg Clicker (HTML/JS)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="other.html">Game - Pond's Training (PICO-8)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/artcharacters2" target="_blank">Article - Advanced Character Design</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/4010059-it-is-that-time-of-t" target="_blank">Art - 2023 Art Summary (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br /> 
		<a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1eYUseCDbP1UuJL4Wj1SbsHl1g6_WCFKDUX_wjE-rCkU/edit" target="_blank">Resources - Toki Pona to Kaliwe Document (GDocs, linked from main website)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.vecderg.com/mini/" target="_blank">Resources - Mini-Linga Travel Phrases + Mini Kore Cheat Sheet</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://itaku.ee/images/697572" target="_blank">Art - Meme ft. Gulusgammamon + Gnar (Itaku)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/3841041-he-s-a-big-fan-of-th" target="_blank">Art - Fidget Rave Party (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/artcharacters" target="_blank">Article - Basic Character Design</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/artcolors" target="_blank">Article - Basic Color Theory</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.vecderg.com/kaliwe/" target="_blank">Resources - Kaliwe Reference + Ube Story + Translator</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.vecderg.com/mini/" target="_blank">Resources - Mini-Linga Travel Phrases + Mini Kore Cheat Sheet</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BJ51mFMaAMg" target="_blank">Video - Ido for Beginners pt.4 (Youtube)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://itaku.ee/images/660359" target="_blank">Art - Commission for Premasaur (Itaku)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/3338253-league-of-legends-au" target="_blank">Art - silly League sketch (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/dracobalance" target="_blank">Article - Game Balance and DracoFighter</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/3239648-meet-the-artist" target="_blank">Art - Meet the Artist (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/3143933-sona-partment-19" target="_blank">Art - SonaPartment #19 (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K5xLTMnYEPw" target="_blank">Video - Ido for Beginners pt.3 (Youtube)</a><br />
		<br />
		</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts1.html</link>
    <pubDate>
      Wed, Sep 18 2024 20:35:29 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>
</channel>
</rss>