<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
<channel>
  <title>Vecderg RSS Feed</title>
  <description>Updates on my posts</description>
  <link>https://vecderg.github.io/</link>
  <lastBuildDate>
	Fri, Jun 20 2025 06:02:25 +0000
  </lastBuildDate>
<!-- TEMPLATE // https://www.unixtimestamp.com/
  <item>
    <title>Insert Title</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
		<p class="normal">
		
		</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts0.html</link>
    <pubDate>
	  Fri, Jun 20 2025 06:02:25 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>
-->

<item>
    <title>June Updates</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
		<p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
		June 20, 2025 - Published 
		</p>

		<p class="normal">
		Hello again! <br />
		<br />
		Recently has been a DOOZY for multiple reasons (not the least of which being Deltarune), but I wanted to stop by my lil website and give y'all another update. <br />
		<br />
		Here's the art I worked on:<br />
		- <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3louutjlns225" target="_blank">Kenny</a> - Yomi Commission (Itaku <a href="https://itaku.ee/images/1096844" target="_blank">1</a> and <a href="https://itaku.ee/images/1096845" target="_blank">2</a>)<br />
		- <a href="https://itaku.ee/images/1097533" target="_blank">Skunk</a> - Tian Commission<br />
		- <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3loslh6pqdc2p" target="_blank">Rudie</a> - Dandy's World fanart<br />
		- <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lq6bonud6s2v" target="_blank">Ravi in the Frutiger Aero world</a> - SonaPartment Mini Spinoff Pt. <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lqaqxs5mr22g" target="_blank">2</a> <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lqfv2o3o522b" target="_blank">3</a> <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lqicd2g4cc2i" target="_blank">4</a> <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lqkxfq5lbk2u" target="_blank">5</a> <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lqnhr3r67s2g" target="_blank">6</a> (<a href="https://itaku.ee/profile/vecderg/gallery/54020" target="_blank">Itaku</a> - all pages)<br />
		<br /> 
		DracoFighter fans, rejoice!!! The first piece of major news in months: the second to last character [DILO] has his sprites <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecdev.bsky.social/post/3lqgjmiry722n" target="_blank">finally finished</a>! The last character to finish is Cyrus, and after that we can finally move onto other aspects (ignoring the still-needed VFX lol).<br /> 
		<br />
		There are 2 videos I published, one being a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7klW9GHsff4" target="_blank">tutorial-overview for Picotron</a>, and the other being a silly Tekken video called <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XE8L5Ttcl7M" target="_blank">The Claudio Right Leg Challenge</a>! I do really hope that more people pick up Picotron; it's a wonderful little system with a lot of potential. <br />
		<br />
		I finished another article: "<a href="https://vecderg.github.io/articles/article8.html" target="_blank">English Features I Don't Like</a>". Yes, I found more ways to rant about English, but this will probably be the last one. <br />
		<br /> 
		Dasopya is in the midst of multiple updates. I expect to finally mark this as the 1.2 update due to the amount of changes, but it will take some time to finalize.<br />
		<br />
		I think that's all I have to report for now, so thank you very much for reading! I have a lot in the works, but I expect things to be going very slowly for the next month or so. dyu a bay i dyuloy e polukyu!<br />
		<br />

		</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts20.html</link>
    <pubDate>
	  Fri, Jun 20 2025 06:02:25 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>

<item>
    <title>Project Update Overviews</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
		<p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
May 17, 2025 - Published 
</p>

<p class="normal">
Howdy, y'all. <br />
<br />
It occurred to me that I haven't done a proper overview -anywhere- about all my projects, so for those of you holding your breath on any project of mine, let's go over all of them. <br />
<br />
I did something like this on Cohost way back (can't find the link) but it's about time for a proper update lol <br />
<br />
You can CTRL+F for the subjects: <br />
Netcode Warriors<br />
DracoFighter 2<br />
Dasopya<br />
Other Games<br />
SonaPartment, Writing<br />
Conclusion<br />
<br />
-- NETCODE WARRIORS --<br />
<br />
For those of you that don't know, Netcode Warriors is a <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/netcodewarriors.sonstudios-dev.com" target="_blank">team project</a> I'm on! We had an <a href="https://youtu.be/K-9W732DYFI" target="_blank">announcement trailer</a> a while back, but yes it is still in development. <br />
<br />
I don't think I'm ALLOWED to say anything meaningful about the development (NDA stuff), but as a team project, this has been one of my highest priorities lately, and I'm basically working on-call. <br />
<br />
I feel personally invested in the success of this project for multiple reasons, so despite not being able to say much of anything on the subject, it has been taking a notable amount of my time and energy over other projects which have been more public.<br />
<br />
-- DRACOFIGHTER 2 --<br />
<br />
In 2023 I estimated that it would take 3-4 years to finish the game, which would put the release at 2026-2027. Life happened to throw a lot of very unexpected things at me (some bad, mostly good), and currently I would put the optimistic release date at 2027-2028.<br />
<br />
(Note: I usually say projects take roughly 3x longer than the estimate lol)<br />
<br />
I may have said before that DracoFighter 2 was a "very high priority project" for me, but nowadays it's less "high priority" as in "I will prioritize this over any other project" and more "there is no timeline where I am alive and DracoFighter 2 does not eventually come out in some form."<br />
<br />
Ironically, that actually means that I'm perfectly fine with taking my sweet time with DracoFighter 2. But I still feel bad for being nearly radio-silent about the project other than <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lmyoa6xs222z" target="_blank">one post</a> that sounded like a pretty lame excuse, so I'll break down everything again at the risk of repeating info from previous posts.<br />
<br />
1) Movesets are 95% complete<br />
<br />
In terms of the actual core gameplay, 95% of the game is essentially complete, which is awesome! I have raw data from the prototype that could be put into a new engine 1:1 and have a perfectly functional fighting game.<br />
<br />
There are some attacks that need to be ironed out or adjusted (most of the 5% is just Cyrus), but these are mainly minor adjustments and most of the time-consuming stuff is out of the way.<br />
<br />
2) Sprites are 90% complete<br />
<br />
Despite my complaining on Twi-- I mean Bluesky, I did a bit more work on sprites to see how I'd do. [DILO] only has about 3 animations left, and Cyrus reuses his old sprites, leaving about 75% of his sprites left to finish.<br />
<br />
For more context on what I said on Bluesky: spriting is MIND-NUMBING. I'm not sure how much I've talked about it before, but despite being well-known for my art, game design IS the main reason I enjoy making games, though spriting takes a massive amount of time.<br />
<br />
DracoFighter 1 only required about half of DF2's sprites (~50 vs ~90), but DF1 BiOS basically took me a month straight of ONLY animating to finish his sprites. People outside game development don't even think about this stuff, but if I go up to anyone who's touched art and tell them "imagine if you had to draw 90 separate drawings to make a single character, now make 8 characters" they'll probably puke.<br />
<br />
Like, I'll do it, and I'd probably be an animator for money, but this is a particular slog worse than DracoFighter 1 specifically because I essentially can't work on anything else. I like switching around different tasks, but right now, it is JUST spriting.<br />
<br />
So, what's the hold-up on the other stuff?<br />
<br />
3) The engine is still incomplete<br />
<br />
If I haven't said it before, BLESS the creator of Sakuga Engine, they are an amazing developer and the engine is basically guaranteed to be the one for DracoFighter 2. However, they are a busy person and DracoFighter 2's engine requires a number of features to be completed in my vision.<br />
<br />
That being said, even if Sakuga Engine was finished literally today, I would still have to spend the time learning the engine, implementing all the sprites and frame data and mechanics, playtesting, etc., and that all takes time!<br />
<br />
4) The everything else<br />
<br />
Now, once we finish ALL of the above, we have some fun fun stuff ahead of us. I plan to contract some friends for assets like music and 3D models, I still have to finish writing story and dialogue, design and implement new game modes, and put in the dreary work for putting the game up on storefronts and getting translations.<br />
<br />
Relative to all the other work... I DON'T actually expect this to take as much time LOL and that's only because spriting is a beast.<br />
<br />
However, that's also at least a year's work, and since I'd like to have extra characters just like DF1 (probably post-launch), there will be a lot of work ahead of me.<br />
<br />
This is why I'm not eager to rush anything lol<br />
<br />
-- DASOPYA --<br />
<br />
Dasopya's been eating good, but slowed down recently. I'm still kind of waiting for interested parties to volunteer to do more stuff, but I think the language just needs more traction which I cannot offer right now.<br />
<br />
Either way, I've been putting in WORK -- we have 795 root words, 336 recorded compounds, 129 loans, a video tutorial, multiple translations, multiple written tutorials (including one available in 7 languages), a instant searchable dictionary, and even a translation aide!<br />
<br />
However, with mentions in a few places, I'll say it explicitly here: at this point, I want to focus on Dasopya as strictly being a hobbyist for-fun project where I don't feel pressured to make a world language or whatever. If I had the energy, I would put in the effort to actually rebrand the project as part artlang and part auxlang, since my goal is just to have fun with it and have other people have fun with it.<br />
<br />
I wrote a more detailed list on the Discord, but to summarize: I do plan to 1) continue updating the wiki, 2) make a text-heavy Pico-8 / Picotron game, and 3) make more oHayde i pya videos, while being more biased against working on projects like translations, new tutorials/learning material, etc.<br />
<br />
These projects are not high priority and will only really be in my free time. However, unlike a lot of my other projects, they actually tend to -decrease- my stress, so I may seem to prioritize it more often than I really "should".<br />
<br />
-- THE OTHER GAMES --<br />
<br />
I've shown off a lot of game ideas over the years, either by prototype or by mention. Demon's Heir, Otto the Otter, Serpent's Tale, etc. There's even ideas that only a few of my friends know about! However, between all the projects above, I really do have my work cut out for me. It would not be unrealistic to say that you might have to wait nearly an entire decade before seeing ANY of these.<br />
<br />
This isn't uncommon for game developers, big or small, so I'm sorry to say that there's a high chance most of these get cancelled. However, mentioning these does help! One of my friends mentioned a game idea I had forgotten about, and it's reignited my interest in continuing it.<br />
<br />
<b>If there is a game idea that has a considerable amount of demand, it might actually encourage me to work on it,</b> even though I generally don't like being pressured into doing certain things.<br />
<br />
But in terms of what's realistic? Here's my list of games that could conceivably get development/news within the next 5 years (note: these priorities change ALL the time and this list could be completely scrambled in a month):<br />
<br />
[Dasopya Game] - smaller game, high chance to be my next release<br />
[Kiru's Game] - VERY excited to tell this story<br />
toki soweli (name pending) - funny language game<br />
Exodus (name pending) - the one my friend mentioned<br />
<br />
Probably abandoned: Li'l Hatchling, Dragon Pet 2, Demon's Heir (kinda lost the big reasons I was interested, but don't worry -- Beewee's story will still be told in one way or another)<br />
<br />
50/50: DragoRescue 2, null, Dog Eat Dog, Serpent's Tail, The Mailman, Otto the Otter (it's just... a basic 2D platformer)
<br />
<br />
-- SONAPARTMENT, WRITING, ETC. --<br />
<br />
If you're holding your breath for the next SonaPartment comic, written article, Youtube video, or even canon Fidget story content, I wouldn't recommend it lol<br />
<br />
These are things I'm only really working on whenever I feel like it. I do have an idea for the next SonaPartment arc, but it's a good bit of work to comic and pretty low priority next to everything else, so I doubt it's happening anytime soon.<br />
<br />
I am throwing out articles randomly which are mentioned here, but I haven't felt very inspired on ideas lately -- most of the stuff I REALLY wanted to write, I've written already, I think. Fidget's story will... continue one day lol<br />
<br />
-- CONCLUSION --<br />
<br />
I thiiiink that's about it for now. There are things I've done since the last post on here, but I'll wait to announce those in the next post since this one's already a big update lol<br />
<br />
Thank you very much for reading and for following my projects! I look forward to the next time I get to do a big infodump.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />


</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts19.html</link>
    <pubDate>
	  Sat, May 17 2025 09:06:08 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>

<item>
    <title>Lotsa Art!</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
		<p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
		May 7, 2025 - Published 
		</p>

		<p class="normal">
		Happy May! <br />
		<br />
		This month I switched gears a bit and took on several commissions, with a few sketches while I was in the mood! <br />
		<br />
		Before those, I'd like to highlight the one article I finished: "<a href="https://vecderg.github.io/articles/article7.html" target="_blank">Just Buy a Flippin' Rice Cooker</a>". <br />
		<br />
		Here are the commissions I finished:<br />
		- <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lnjnmmhxjc2l" target="_blank">Flower Hug</a> - 0SilentMoon Commission ft. Aphra (<a href="https://itaku.ee/images/1086104" target="_blank">Itaku</a>)<br />
		- <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lnrfojznh22g" target="_blank">Nidoqueen</a> - Premasaur Commission (<a href="https://itaku.ee/images/1087706" target="_blank">Itaku</a>)<br />
		- <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lntrexjelc2z" target="_blank">Icarus</a> - TexanSoda Commission (<a href="https://itaku.ee/images/1088275" target="_blank">Itaku</a>)<br />
		- <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lo5ab7q3uc2k" target="_blank">VTuber</a> - BassBoostWoof Commission <br />
		- <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lo5wq3ike22o" target="_blank">Star Rail</a> - Tamanegi-K Commission (<a href="https://itaku.ee/images/1090401" target="_blank">Itaku</a>)<br />
		- <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lohjxp4usk24" target="_blank">Mango</a> - Pieraite Commission (<a href="https://itaku.ee/images/1093039" target="_blank">Itaku</a>)<br />
		<br /> 
		And the other art I did:<br />
		- <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3ln7ryuxqy224" target="_blank">Aphra Gift Art</a><br />
		- <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lo3gwevx7c2i" target="_blank">Fidget and Ube in Glaggleland</a><br />
		- <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lo7z5pmzfk2i" target="_blank">Waffle Fry Tragedy</a><br />
		<br /> 
		As always, thank you all for reading, and hope you enjoy!<br />
		<br />

		</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts18.html</link>
    <pubDate>
	  Wed, May 07 2025 23:08:06 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>

<item>
    <title>Translator and Archive</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
		<p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
		April 17, 2025 - Published 
		</p>

		<p class="normal">
		Happy April! <br />
		<br />
		So far this month, I archived the kyle14 2025 event <a href="https://itaku.ee/profile/vecderg/gallery/53162" target="_blank">on Itaku</a> (where the comic is actually ordered this time!) and have pushed out <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/dasopya.bsky.social/post/3lmxvdulwrk2j" target="_blank">Dasopya's 1.1.3 update</a>, changing some words and adding a handful of new ones. <br />
		<br />
		Dasopya's development is going pretty smoothly! We're currently at 793 root words, just a bit shy of the 800 goal, though I am considering passing it. The most notable achievement was my completion of <a href="https://vecderg.github.io/kutokopo/samukopo.html#pyabyo" target="_blank">the translation aide</a> (yes, Dasopya already has something close to a translator!), which should majorly help learners speed up understanding of texts. <br />
		<br />
		I also finally finished up a draft of the Wikibooks-style tutorial on <a href="https://vecderg.github.io/kutokopo/dasopya.html" target="_blank">the Kutokopo page</a>, but it still needs some updates and proofreading. When it's finished, hopefully it'll help as a resource that actually explains things and doesn't just brush over 10 grammatical concepts! <br />
		<br />
		Between the busy-ness of everything, I haven't been able to get around to working on much unrelated to Dasopya, but for the Dasopya fans, just know that I'm working on another decently-sized project in my free time...<br />
		<br />
		I also finished one article, which is related to languages again:<br />
		- <a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/languagelaziness" target="_blank">How Different Languages Allow Laziness</a><br />
		<br /> 
		And for those looking for art, I did <a href="https://itaku.ee/images/1076945" target="_blank">an FF14 themed commission</a> for my good friend Pyke.<br />
		<br />
		Thank you for reading! See you all in the next one.<br />
		<br />

		</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts17.html</link>
    <pubDate>
	  Thu, Apr 17 2025 07:56:14 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>

<item>
    <title>kyle14 Approaches</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
		<p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
	March 26, 2025 - Published 
	</p>

	<p class="normal">
	April 1st is almost here! In preparation, I finally moved all the kyle14 lore and information off of Twitter so that everyone can access everything. <br />
	<br />
	You can either find it on <a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/characters#h.415gv095dj19" target="_blank">my Characters Page</a>, or just go to <a href="https://www.vecderg.com/kyle2019" target="_blank">https://www.vecderg.com/kyle2019</a> and <a href="https://www.vecderg.com/kyle2020" target="_blank">https://www.vecderg.com/kyle2020</a> which link to everything.<br />
	<br />
	It's a lot to catch up on, but this year will have major lore consequences, so I do encourage people to look if they're invested (though even if you aren't, I'm sure it'll be entertaining!). The event will primarily be on Bluesky, and probably be archived elsewhere afterwards. <br />
	<br />
	Most of the other news is more conlang stuff. I released another unscripted Youtube video, this time about "<a href="https://youtu.be/ur3BFKuBATY" target="_blank">The Auxlang Problem</a>". People seemed to enjoy the Smash video, so I'm very happy that these are doing well, because they're fun to make (even if still difficult!).<br />
	<br />
	The <a href="https://vecderg.github.io/kutokopo/sadilusi.html#deutsch" target="_blank">German translation</a> of the Dasopya intro has been finished! Huge thank you to Habanero030 who volunteered to do this.<br />
	<br />
	I only finished 1 article, and it's more of an informal article to complain lol:<br />
	- <a href="https://vecderg.github.io/articles/article6.html" target="_blank">Auxlang Critiques I Don't Really Like</a><br />
	<br /> 
	Unrelated to auxlangs, I have finally posted a piece of art! It's traditional pencil <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3llcsdfgfnc2u" target="_blank">gift art</a> for my good friend HeroofHatz.<br />
	<br />
	Don't worry, there'll be a lot more art very soon... see you after the kyle14 event! And thank you for reading as always.<br />
	<br />

</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts16.html</link>
    <pubDate>
	  Wed, Mar 26 2025 23:52:33 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>

<item>
    <title>The Busy is Rolling</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
		<p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
March 2, 2025 - Published 
</p>

<p class="normal">
It's been a bit!<br />
<br />
Reading the previous entry is kind of funny, because the ball stopped rolling almost immediately after posting it. The reason? Well, to put it simply... I moved! I don't like talking too much about my personal life in public posts, but I will say that it's taken up a lot of my time, and anyone who knows me personally can ask for more details.<br />
<br />
Still, that hasn't stopped me from having a lot more to update on! I enjoy doing projects during my free time...<br />
<br />
My most major announcement is the release of my PICO-8 game <a href="https://www.lexaloffle.com/bbs/?tid=147601" target="_blank">Konakin</a>! It's a 5-15 min open world Frogger adventure featuring text exclusively in my auxlang Dasopya, but is 100% playable without knowledge of the language. <br />
<br />
Despite primarily being made for Dasopya, this was an idea I've had for a while, and the first "real" PICO-8 game I've made since <a href="https://vecderg.github.io/p8games/pond.html" target="_blank">the other one</a> essentially feels like a prototype. Even though many things can be difficult in it, I love using PICO-8 and being able to just release tiny games that work perfectly on websites for both mobile and desktop. People don't understand how magical that is! It's also mentioned on the site, but many thanks to my friend SandwichDeer for helping out -- he composed the title theme!<br />
<br />
Speaking of Dasopya, I also had a friend help out in translating <a href="https://vecderg.github.io/kutokopo/sadilusi.html#espanol" target="_blank">the language's introduction</a> to Spanish -- many thanks to Snow! I am still looking for translators for other languages, if anyone is willing.<br />
<br />
I also released <a href="https://youtu.be/WZxj1mHFCpA" target="_blank">a Youtube video</a>! It's a discussion on Smash Bros' (and general platform fighters') design analyzed as a fighting game, which is a subject I have surprisingly not seen on Youtube. It's unscripted and a bit unorganized, but I would love to do more videos like this if people enjoy (and they seemed to very much!).<br />
<br />
I finished writing several articles:<br />
- <a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/targetaudience" target="_blank">How Target Audiences Work</a> - introduction mainly for gamedevs<br />
- <a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/balancetop" target="_blank">Why are Games Balanced Around Top Level Play?</a><br />
- <a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/motioninputs" target="_blank">Practical Use Cases for Motion Inputs</a><br />
- <a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/englishfacts" target="_blank">5 English Facts you (Probably) Didn't Know</a><br />
- <a href="https://vecderg.github.io/articles/article5.html" target="_blank">Cool (Natural) Languages I Like</a><br />

<br /> 
Aaaaand that's about it! Thank you all for reading, and if you still follow this RSS feed... I appreciate you!!!<br />
<br />

</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts15.html</link>
    <pubDate>
	  Mon, Mar 03 2025 06:14:41 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>

<item>
    <title>The Ball is Rolling</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
		<p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
January 24, 2025 - Published 
</p>

<p class="normal">
Hello again!<br />
<br />
After a bit of a break, I've finally gotten the ball rolling again and made a lot of great progress. Maybe I can keep it going, maybe it'll stop soon, but either way there's some big stuff to mention.<br />
<br />
First of all, Dasopya finally has a <a href="https://youtu.be/DbpzzWu761Q" target="_blank">Youtube tutorial</a>! This has been planned for a long while, but was only able to be created now that the language has reached a stable spot. If you wanted to get into the language but have been intimidated by all the documents, please give it a look!<br />
<br />
Accompanying this guide is <a href="https://youtu.be/l8v2-3-j3eQ" target="_blank">the first video</a> for the official Dasopya Youtube channel! It's a quick thing I put together so the channel has something in it, but it's my hope that I can make more immersion-style videos to help the language going. <br />
<br />
I've also been working on <a href="https://vecderg.github.io/kutokopo/sadilusi.html" target="_blank">this introduction to Dasopya</a>, which will be translated to as many languages as I can. It's currently available in English, Esperanto, and toki pona! Dasopya's development will be much slower now as it increases in stability, so that means we get to have a much larger focus on creating Dasopya media.<br />
<br />
Also, good news for DracoFighter fans! I posted a new video showing off some basic gameplay of 2 of the new DracoFighter 2 characters: <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecdev.bsky.social/post/3lfvn6lxf3k2v" target="_blank">https://bsky.app/profile/vecdev.bsky.social/post/3lfvn6lxf3k2v</a><br />
<br />
I'm still working within the DracoFighter 1 engine, but the news of the new engine has brought me enough energy to continue spriting. [DILO] now has 7 new animations (22 sprites in total) with about 9 animations left to finish.<br />
<br />
I wrote a few language-related articles that will be hosted here, exclusively:<br />
- <a href="https://vecderg.github.io/articles/article3.html" target="_blank">Why Words are Fake</a><br />
- <a href="https://vecderg.github.io/articles/article4.html" target="_blank">English is not an Easy Language</a><br />
<br /> 
I also had a funny <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lfiyzyiruk2u" target="_blank">art-adjacent post</a> blow up on Bluesky recently and hit 500 likes, so that happened. Not the first time I've had a PMD post blow up, nor a piece I threw together on Paint.NET...<br />
<br />
Anyway, I did want to give some apologies to the people following me for art. I'm not really the type to apologize for stuff like that (I think both me and my audience understand that I'm the type of person that just posts whatever I feel like), but it's been almost 2 months since my last real art post of something new, so I still feel obliged to.<br />
<br />
I'm partly out of my weird art block phase, but I've still been struggling a lot with rediscovering what it is that I enjoy about art, so it's something that I'll have to continue processing later when I'm not in the middle of so many things. Since this is currently the only site that I don't feel a million eyes on me, I may talk about it more in a future post.<br />
<br />
For now, there is still a lot that I very much enjoy! And again, a huge thank you to everyone for your support.<br />
<br />

</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts14.html</link>
    <pubDate>
	  Sat, Jan 25 2025 02:08:48 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Hello New Year (Reflection + DracoFighter 2 + Dasopya Updates)</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
		<p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
		January 2, 2025 - Published 
		</p>

		<p class="normal">
		Happy new year!<br />
		<br />
		(This post will probably get a bit rambley, but for those skimming, this post will have <i><b>semi-major news for DracoFighter 2 and Dasopya</b></i>, even if neither have things that are particularly finished yet!) <br />
		<br />
		I've spent a good amount of time trying to absorb some of the events of this year, and I think it'll still take a long time before I remotely do.<br />
		<br />
		While filing away a backup of my art for the year, I remarked to a friend, "Wow, there's a lot less this year," and he told me, "Yeah, because you've spent most of your time on those sprites, right?" and then I had to go, "Oh yeah, those sprites." <br />
		<br />
		I was so deep into my side project of making an entirely new language that I completely forgot I had been spent the first ~9 months of that year making sprites for a game that didn't exist yet..... which I suppose is not something everyone can say?? <br />
		<br />
		-- DRACOFIGHTER 2 UPDATES -- 
		<br />
		<br />
		I'll get right into DracoFighter 2 first. Being the new year and all, I want to be a little self-congratulatory for a bit, because I feel like I deserve it. This year was the first year I completed all the sprites for a single character, being Draco with 90 sprites (including the reused ones)!<br />
		<br />
		Afterwards, I finished all the sprites for: Plexie, BiOS, [STEGO], [TREX], and [RAPTOR]! I completed a notable number of sprites for [DILO], and Cyrus still has many reusable sprites. This is a huge amount of work!!! Every completed character has roughly 80-100 sprites, so accounting for sprites already completed, I drew roughly 350+ sprites this year! That's like a drawing a day!! That's crazy to me!! <br />
		<br />
		For reference, every DF1 character had about 50 sprites each, meaning that in this single year I drew more completed sprites than the entirety of DF1. I'll probably be able to do a more accurate count sometime when I have the DF2 project set up, since right now everything's in folders which makes it very difficult to count. With that being said...<br />
		<br />
		WE HAVE AN ENGINE!!! It's not completed yet, but I'm unbelievably happy that an actual real engine exists now that fits every criteria I need. It's free, it's open source, and it already has completely functional rollback!! Even if this isn't the engine I end up going with, there's a lot of relief in just seeing this exist, and there's a high likelihood it gets finished: <a href="https://github.com/NoisyChain/Sakuga-Engine" target="_blank">https://github.com/NoisyChain/Sakuga-Engine</a> <br />
		<br />
		I already tested putting Draco in with basic functionality, and it's very well-made! There's a lot of eyes on it, so I hope it goes well. I only talked about it in an update a while ago, but man the whole engine issue has really been bothering me more than I realized...<br />
		<br />
		Plans for DracoFighter 2 haven't changed much. The engine still isn't finished, so I'll continue to sprite when I can, though I'm still suffering from some artblock most likely caused by all the spriting. After I finish both Cyrus and [DILO], we'll most likely be looking at engine implementation if it's finished (or nearly finished), or more assets if it's not (VFX, UI, story text, etc.).<br />
		<br />
		-- DASOPYA UPDATES -- <br />
		<br />
		Dasopya really did kind of come out of nowhere, and I probably wouldn't believe you if you told me at the beginning of the year that making a new international auxiliary language would be my 6+ month project of the year. Well, actually, I probably would believe you, but would be rather annoyed LOL <br />
		<br />
		As I update the project more, my own personal enjoyment of it increases as well. I have a mini update being dubbed v1.1.1 (yes, Minecraft style) that adjusts a handful of words while adding about a dozen new ones. You can read the changes listed on the spreadsheet <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1c64g6Yftybzoe9KeHm_WyeTTtMec23YiMDap351RxFw/edit?gid=1731217827#gid=1731217827&range=A278" target="_blank">here</a>. They're not final yet, and will be given about a week before they're solidified and reflected in existing learning/story material outside the spreadsheet.<br />
		<br />
		Dasopya has a handful of other very notable announcements. We're setting up our wiki on Miraheze instead of Fandom, because Fandom, and you can find the new wiki <a href="https://dasopya.miraheze.org/" target="_blank">here</a>. It's still rather bare-bones, but it's ready to be populated with articles.<br />
		<br />
		We also now have a <a href="https://vecderg.github.io/kutokopo/samukopo.html" target="_blank">searchable dictionary</a>!! No more spreadsheet scrolling and Ctrl+F, just use a search bar! This will also include the new v1.1.1 words when the update is solidified. It's a little rough around the edges since it's pure HTML/JS I made by myself, but it was a very fun challenge since I haven't done many similar projects at all.<br />
		<br />
		The Dasopya Discord also created <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/dasopya.bsky.social/post/3lefyr24ork2j" target="_blank">their own script</a>, bukudoli! This was mainly the work of Goji (@gojiberry.cc on Bsky), so huge thank you to them. <br />
		<br />
		I get a good amount of feedback in the Discord, but the existing script (pyalibu) got WAY more unanimous criticism than I ever expected, so I wasn't unhappy turning the challenge over to the members. It seems like I have a lot to learn about writing scripts, something I didn't realize would have so many unintended issues.
		<br />
		<br />
		The last real note for Dasopya is that I spent December joining the Lexember hashtag, and posted a Dasopya word (almost) every day! I had only just found out about it at the beginning of December, so this was also a fun little project. You can find it <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/dasopya.bsky.social/post/3lene5csxak2l" target="_blank">here</a>.<br />
		<br />
		I'm very very happy with Dasopy's progress over the year, and only hope to continue to give it a bigger and brighter future! <br />
		<br />
		-- OTHER UPDATES + REFLECTION -- <br />
		<br />
		The last notes are mainly for art stuff, which I can just list here.<br />
		- <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lcm7ptkqz22e" target="_blank">Experimental art pieces</a> for SandwichDeer and FCBandanaDee <br />
		- <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lcw2kw6kb22e" target="_blank">Updated unhelpful guide to my sonas</a> <br />
		- <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3le4vwoirls22" target="_blank">2024 art summary</a> <br />
		<br />
		Looking back on the year... is really weird. It feels more like a transitional period for me than anything. A lot of really big, important things happened to me, but none of them have LED anywhere yet. I might have 600+ DracoFighter 2 sprites sitting on my computer right now, but nowhere to put them. I might have a completed language, but nowhere to use it. I'm very happy and proud of the work I did, but I have a strong feeling that 2025 is where the really big things are going to happen. Which is kinda exciting and intimidating!<br />
		<br />
		This was the year I completed my conlang tutorial series. This was the year I went to Europe for the first time! This was the year I became active on Bluesky. This was the year I said goodbye to Cohost.<br />
		<br />
		This was the year I started posts on this website! This was the year I learned how to use RSS. This was the year I made most of the DF2 sprites, and made Dasopya, and quit Tumblr, and made a Neocities account, and met many wonderful people I'm now able to call my friends. That's a lot, isn't it...<br />
		<br />
		Oh, I almost forgot. I had a yearly tradition on Twitter where I would post about my yearly goals, after catching up on last year's. Since Twitter isn't a good archive anymore, I'll post about the past years here, too.<br />
		<br />
		"2023 hobbyist goals:<br />
		- get a proper prototype for dracofighter 2! <br />
		- release a small side game <br />
		- get to a conversational level in at least 1 language <br />
		- make a pico8 app" <br />
		<br />
		On technicalities, I've essentially done all of these! I released <a href="https://vecderg.github.io/htmlgames.html">Pond's Training</a>, a small PICO-8 game. I didn't complete a full prototype for DracoFighter 2, but the gameplay is fleshed out on the DF1 engine, and I tested the new one. Finalmente, puedo hablar español, pero no estoy muy bueno...<br />
		<br />
		I'm unsure what my 2024 goals will be, but I can go with:<br />
		- release a small game with Dasopya <br />
		- finish all the base DF2 cast sprites <br />
		- find a new hobby <br />
		<br />
		Aiming kind of low here because I have a lot of IRL goals that I won't be disclosing here... but I'll note some unofficial goals 1) making music which has been on the backlog, 2) making a PICO-8 / Picotron game because I just love those things, and 3) possibly learning a new game engine just because.<br />
		<br />
		Either way, very happy with the progress for my goals, since even if they're based on technicalities, I usually don't expect to hit all my goals at once lol<br />
		<br />
		-- YEARLY GOAL ARCHIVE -- <br />
		<br />
		Thank you all lots for reading!! I'll dedicate the rest of the post just to archiving my old yearly goals, but I hope you all have a wonderful new year's.<br />
		<br />
		"2019 goals (which i will look back on and laugh at in a year): <br />
		- learn lineart <br />
		- proper art studies <br /> 
		- learn 3d animation <br />
		- do 2d animation  <br />
		- make a game <br />
		- find direction for my youtube channel  <br />
		- reach 1k subs <br />
		- make everyone furries <br />
		- become all-powerful <br />
		- gain world domination" <br />
		<br />
		"ok but more realistically <br />
		- make a 1+ min 2d animation <br />
		- finish a rigged 3d model and animate it <br />
		- finish a game, even a small one <br />
		- gain world domination <br />
		<br />
		i should be able to do that in a year, right?" <br />
		<br />
		2020 reflection: "forgot i made this and actually ig i did a few of these" <br />
		<br />
		2022 goals: "past me was a scrub and didnt make any more yearly goals so here's 2022 goals: <br />
		- publish dracofighter <br />
		- get a game out with networking <br />
		- finish a realism drawing <br />
		- finish a 1min+ animation <br />
		- 3d work!! (game? animation? model)" <br />
		<br />
		2023 reflection: <br />
		"v happy with this year, has been p wild! but i feel that i made a lot of progress personally and professionally 😊  <br />
		<br />
		i can comfortably say i finished half of these (DF, realism painting, 3d model) which is honestly more than i expected" <br />
		<br />
		2023 goals: "prob gonna keep this year's hobbyist goals more tame while i focus more on professional goals: <br />
		- make 3d game prototype with animated models <br />
		- make a 2d animation (this goal is like 3 years running LOL) <br />
		- use less TWITTER <br />
		<br />
		will also unofficially include learning pico8 and composing some music as goals (maybe even learning piano!), but i don't really want them to be focuses <br />
		<br />
		im also already learning pico8 at this moment anyway so hmm hmmMM" <br />
		<br />
		2024 reflection (now on Vecdevg): <br />
		"i feel obliged to continue this tradition lol<br />
		<br />
		kept my goals low for this year but it's still surprising to me that i kind of met all of them (3d prototype demon's heir, 2d animation dracofighter 2 sprites on technicality, and definitely using less twitter LOL) <br />
		<br />
		achievements for this year were unexpected, but i'm v happy with what i pulled together<br />
		<br />
		with that being said, yes! i should have a lot more time for dracofighter 2 next year<br />
		<br />
		there's still a lot of work to do..."<br />
		<br />
		<br />

		</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts13.html</link>
    <pubDate>
	  Thu, Jan 02 2025 10:20:45 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Dasopya 1.1 Update and Discord</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
		<p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
		December 10, 2024 - Published 
		</p>

		<p class="normal">
		Hi, so it's time to go back on my word a bit!!<br />
		<br />
		My goal for the 1.0 update was to pause any major updates, but out of the blue, I had a wonderful person reach out to me -- and review the ENTIRE vocabulary one by one.<br />
		<br />
		There were many good changes to be had, so instead of ignoring it in favor of my nice neat number, I decided to implement all the changes we agreed on. The alternatives would have been to either 1) change nothing despite agreeing there were issues, or 2) to change it all later on when there's a lot more material and speakers -- both of which wouldn't be ideal, so 1.1 it is. <br />
		<br />
		It's worth mentioning that I did have some reservations about 1.0 but released it anyway since I didn't have much motivation to review everything. It was also released with the assumption that nobody was interested in doing a large amount of collaboration. I probably don't need to justify my decision to the 5 total people actually following the language, I just felt a bit self-conscious about saying "this is the final big update" and then doing another big update a week later lol<br />
		<br />
		Either way, here's the <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lcyjembvwk2i" target="_blank">Bluesky announcement</a> that includes a link to the changes!<br />
		<br />
		As I say in the thread, most of the changes were word removals to keep the base vocabulary as stable as possible, but there's a possibility that some of them come back later. By removing the words we were uncertain about, the words that were left would ensure that things like translations and tutorials wouldn't have to be changed. This should be the ACTUAL point where the base vocabulary should stay nearly untouched for the foreseeable future, minus word additions, where new words will be more subject to change.<br />
		<br />
		And of course, big thank you to the person who took all the time to help out, Aronora! I don't know which socials they have, so here's <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@Aronora" target="_blank">their Youtube channel</a>. Their name has been added to the founding document and the vocab sheet.<br />
		<br />
		Also: Dasopya has <a href="https://discord.gg/ZpPSRhU3YF" target="_blank">a Discord</a> now (Bluesky announcement <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/dasopya.bsky.social/post/3lcyk2js4pc2z" target="_blank">here</a>)! I knew how important it was to make a community where people could speak together, but I didn't want to moderate another server, until one of my friends volunteered to help. All the people volunteering to help has been a huge honor...<br />
		<br />
		Speaking of which, last bit of news (ignoring anything non-Dasopya for this update) is that another person came to my DMs to start off <a href="https://dasopya.fandom.com/wiki/Dasopya_Wiki" target="_blank">a Dasopya wiki</a>!! It's very bare-bones, but it's worth mentioning in this update. Big thank you to Chabi!<br />
		<br />
		I know Dasopya is a pretty niche project, but that just means I appreciate the support all the more. Thank you for reading! There is more to come.<br />
		<br />

		</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts12.html</link>
    <pubDate>
	  Wed, Dec 11 2024 02:18:11 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Dasopya Release and More!</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
		<p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
		December 2, 2024 - Published 
		</p>

		<p class="normal">
		It's finally HEEEEEREEE! <br />
		<br />
		My auxlang Dasopya has announced its official 1.0 release on <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lcbvsg3op22d" target="_blank">Bluesky</a> and <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/auxlangs/comments/1h4ivm6/dasopya_10_stability_announcement/" target="_blank">Reddit</a>! That means the language will now be paused for any major changes (other than vocab additions), meaning that it'll be safe to learn from and create Dasopya content.<br />
		<br />
		The language will probably still get changes in the future, but it will take much more time and consideration than previous changes. Either way, all changes will be recorded in <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1c64g6Yftybzoe9KeHm_WyeTTtMec23YiMDap351RxFw/" target="_blank">the spreadsheet</a>. Please consider giving <a href="https://www.dasopya.com/" target="_blank">the main website</a> a look -- Dasopya has been my big project for the last several months!<br />
		<br />
		Other than that, I have a bunch of assorted news to show.<br />
		<br />
		New articles:<br />
		-  <a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/fightingsimple" target="_blank">Opinion: Why Fighting Games are Simple, Actually</a> <br />
		-  <a href="https://www.vecderg.com/esperantoenglish" target="_blank">Learn Esperanto by Doing Nothing</a> <br />
		-  <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1sCqJVoZOZwz1AEm6L2rh7YBKMR6VXKGdFjwPdQMTPHc/" target="_blank">Behind Dasopya</a> (personal thoughts/feelings on the language, Google Doc) <br />
		<br />
		I have another ref sheet commission for my good friend Eijin, only on <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lbdpgdqohs2x" target="_blank">Bluesky</a>.<br />
		<br />
		I updated the kyle2023 ARG so that it's still possible to solve, since it was broken from various changes between Twitter, Discord, and Cohost. Like before, you can start the hunt from <a href="https://vecderg.itch.io/kyle2023" target="_blank">the Itch page</a>. I've also reposted <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lbgjwbfrw22j" target="_blank">the kyle14 ref sheets</a> for anyone to catch up on the lore before next year's event!<br />
		<br />
		It's also still a work in progress, but I might as well show off the preview for <a href="https://vecderg.github.io/kutokopo/dasopya.html" target="_blank">my "Wikibooks" course for Dasopya</a>, which I made from scratch since I wasn't sure if it'd be approved for the actual website. Am I making too many tutorials for this language? Maybe, but I also wanted more material for the language that wasn't just more Google Docs and Google Sites lol <br />
		<br />
		But yeah, that's about it! I only have one thing left on my list and that's Sonja Lang following me on Bluesky which is awesome but I'm not really sure how to comment on it?? I reposted my toki pona <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lbq3dgty722p" target="_blank">Hyde art piece</a> on Bluesky in her honor...<br />
		<br />
		Thank you all for reading!! I'll probably make another post before Christmas, but if I don't, I hope you all have a wonderful holiday season.<br />
		<br />
		</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts11.html</link>
    <pubDate>
	  Tue, Dec 03 2024 00:03:10 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Lotsa New Stuff!</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
		<p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
		November 17, 2024 - Published 
		</p>

		<p class="normal">
		Howdy! Been a bit longer than I wanted, but that just means there's more to show! <br />
		<br />
		Recently has been pretty weird where it's been difficult to focus on tasks I've wanted to, and I think part of it was just having a massive distracting backlog. So, I really wanted to hack away at it to get myself a clearer head. And I think it helped!<br />
		<br />
		Starting with my biggest project, <a href="https://youtu.be/ee1biWWYMbs" target="_blank">my Elefen tutorial</a> has finally come out!! I started the script like over a year ago and finally got around to finishing it, which is a huge weight off my back. This is the last planned video in my auxlang series (which doesn't include my own languages), but it's been fun!<br />
		<br />
		I've considered making a video on Esperanto and/or toki pona, but due to the amount of existing resources, I just don't feel it's worth the large amount of effort since there's already many existing resources out there, and my main goal was the highlight languages that did not yet have a proper video tutorials. There are also currently no other auxlangs that have caught a large enough interest that I want to put the time in for research/recording/video editing, though I do eventually want to make a video on Manmino and have some curiosity about Lidepla.<br />
		<br />
		I have also written several articles! The titles are:<br />
		-  <a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/partialaphantasia" target="_blank">Being an Artist with Partial Aphantasia</a> <br />
		-  <a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/balancefun" target="_blank">Game Balance - Why Balance Means Fun</a> <br />
		-  <a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/defenseminimalism" target="_blank">In Defense of Minimalism</a> <br />
		-  <a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/lazyproductive" target="_blank">How Being Lazy Made Me More Productive</a> <br />
		<br />
		The last thing to show is a commission I finished for my good ol regular Premasaur: <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3lazctlfp322s" target="_blank">Bluesky</a> / <a href="https://itaku.ee/images/974868" target="_blank">Itaku</a> <br />
		<br />
		While I don't imagine this piece to stand out that much compared to some of my other art, it's one of my favorites out of my recent artwork for the pure fact that this is probably what feels the most "my style" to me, which feels very refreshing! Based on what I asked earlier, most people seem to associate me with my SonaPartment style, which is totally fine and cool! But also the "furry in a dynamic pose doing an attack in the air" will always be my genre.<br />
		<br />
		One more thing to mention that I don't have a ton to show for: I spent like 8 hours straight working on Dasopya the day before yesterday LOL<br />
		<br />
		I made 50+ changes to the vocbulary to essentially get rid of all my minor gripes, then had to update every existing piece of Dasopya media to match it. It was a lot of work but it'll be super worth it, because (minus the beginning of the language) this is planned to be the biggest update I'll EVER make to Dasopya, past and future -- otherwise, changing all media again will be much more of a pain.<br />
		<br />
		I wanted to also do this when the vocabulary was nearly finished, so that the last few words could be analyzed more strictly when added, making the process easier. All this work, of course, is for a very specific goal: Dasopya is almost at 1.0!!!<br />
		<br />
		Version numbers are a funny thing to put on a language, but it's rather common for conlangs, especially since they're marks of stability. Dasopya is a minimalistic language, so once it's done, it's meant to be donezo. While updates are planned for the future, they're likely to be relatively minimal after 1.0, only adding words that are very important and ideally making little to no changes to the existing vocabulary. <br />
		<br />
		Again, I don't have much to show since I've mainly just been updating existing content (do update your notes if you have any), but I did make a nearly-empty Bluesky account just to take the handle: <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/dasopya.bsky.social" target="_blank">https://bsky.app/profile/dasopya.bsky.social</a> <br />
		<br />
		As usual, thank you all lots for reading!!! The next time you get a post from me, hopefully a new language will have officially been born.
		<br />
		<br />
		</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts10.html</link>
    <pubDate>
	  Sun, Nov 17 2024 11:12:38 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>


  <item>
    <title>Fixed last link</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
		<p class="normal">
			Last post link was wrong and should now be corrected!! This post should also lead to the correct link.
		</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts9.html</link>
    <pubDate>
	  Sun, Nov 03 2024 22:24:56 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>More Writing (and Art!)</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
		<p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
		November 3, 2024 - Published 
		</p>

		<p class="normal">
		Howdy! I've been preoccupied by various things, but now I've got a lot of stuff to show.<br />
		<br />
		I had a good bit of energy but wasn't sure how to direct it, before realizing that instead of forcing myself to do things I didn't want to do, I could just fully commit to writing stuff that I did want to. So that's what I did!	<br />
		<br />
		First is the most major one, another short story about Fidget that features Ube, titled: <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1Kj3b6p1o0qXsMNz0rpbmTk2AvylwJcftfJ6_UgrCmz0/" target="_blank">A Woodworker</a><br />
		NOTE -- If you haven't read the past stories, this requires the context of "Rival Incoming," and by extension, "The View Above the Clouds." You can find both here: <a href="../dragonscavern.html">https://vecderg.github.io/dragonscavern.html</a><br />
		<br />
		I've also written 3 articles on my main website! There are 2 opinion articles: <a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/esperanto1" target="_blank">Why I Love Esperanto!</a> and <a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/genrepurist" target="_blank">Why I'm a Game Genre Purist (Kinda)</a><br />
		<br />
		And one analysis of Jack Garland (aka the "I want to kill Chaos" guy) and why 1-dimensional characters can totally be cool: <a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/jackgarland" target="_blank">Design Analysis: Jack Garland</a><br />
		<br />
		I did get a brief bit of art motivation that I hope to carry into the rest of the week! First I made a new beluga mascot for Dasopya which you can now see <a href="https://www.dasopya.com/" target="_blank">on the main website</a>, who I frankly created because I didn't want my robot mascot to become associated with the recent push for AI in conlang communities. I still plan for both of these lil guys to be co-mascots, but just not today. Here they are side by side, so do lemme know what you think!<br />
		<br />
		<img style="width:40%" src="img/dosodaw.png">
		<img style="width:40%" src="img/ludwa.png"><br />
		<br />
		Finally, I did a quick drawing for my recent Webfishing spree. As of the time of writing, I have over 30 hours in the game and bought out every store just today! Of course, this meant I had to draw a meme. It has two versions, both of which are available on Bluesky and Itaku, but I'll just be linking one from each. Here's the <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3l7zkqp4t6i27" target="_blank">meme version on Bluesky</a>, and the <a href="https://itaku.ee/images/971640" target="_blank">alt version on Itaku</a>. <br />
		<br />
		Ironically, this is actually a bit of a milestone because it's the first time I've done a non-painting lineless drawing in forever. Unfortunately, I did not put much effort into it LOL<br />
		<br />
		Either way, thank you all for the support as always. I always appreciate it when people enjoy the silly things I put out into the internet. And if I do put this post out as planned on Bluesky, then hi new people!! I hope you all enjoy your time on this website.<br />
		<br />
		Oh! Last note, I added a new RSS icon on the front page which I made from scratch in Inkscape, so I wanted to make it 100% free to use for anyone with or without credit. Here's the raw SVG for your full resolution needs: <a href="../img/rss.svg" target="_blank">https://vecderg.github.io/img/rss.svg</a>
		<br />
		<br />
		</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts9.html</link>
    <pubDate>
      Sun, Nov 03 2024 09:50:08 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Articles</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
		<p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
		October 21, 2024 - Published 
		</p>

		<p class="normal">
		Quick post for quick news!<br />
		<br />
		I have 2 OPINION articles to share, one here, and one on my main website. Potential hot takes may be waiting for you.<br />
		<br />
		The first is the one on my main website which I posted weeks ago but forgot to mention. It's titled "How Subjective is Art?" and you can read it here: <a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/artsubjective" target="_blank">https://www.vecderg.com/articles/artsubjective</a><br />
		<br />
		The other is "My Thoughts on the International Auxlang" which you can read here: <a href="../articles/article2.html">https://vecderg.github.io/articles/article2.html</a><br />
		<br />
		Since everyone uses it and it's most likely safe, I brought back my CBox, but it will stay quarantined in the <a href="../other.html">Other</a> tab rather than the front page to avoid potential issues.<br />
		<br />
		Again, thank you all for the support! I've gotten so many followers on Bluesky just in the past few days...
		<br />
		<br />
		</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts8.html</link>
    <pubDate>
      Tue, Oct 22 2024 01:31:15 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>

  
  <item>
    <title>Peter Rabbit</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
		<p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
		October 18, 2024 - Published 
		</p>

		<p class="normal">
		Lots of news! Despite the title, I actually want to first note the changes on my website. 
		<br />
		<br />
		I've already expressed some concern about my website having a glitch where it becomes unclickable, so I've removed every JS script from the front page other than the webrings, since those are kind of important for me to have. 
		<br />
		<br />
		As the front page now says, please let me know if there are any other issues (even though I'll be rather unsure how to proceed if they continue). I only knew that it was still broken because someone messaged me on <a href="https://www.vecderg.com/feedback-and-comments" target="_blank">my main website's comment system</a>, so you can use that if you can't reach me elsewhere.
		<br />
		<br />
		Second, HUGE progress on Dasopya!! We've finally hit 750 words, and I finished my biggest translation so far, which is The Tale of Peter Rabbit:
		<a href="https://www.dasopya.com/readings/the-tale-of-peter-rabbit" target="_blank">https://www.dasopya.com/readings/the-tale-of-peter-rabbit</a>
		<br />
		<br />
		This is a story very near and dear to my heart, so I was very happy to finish it, though it took me about a whole week straight. I also finished <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/133gbKFGP3ubczpCkUwKM1cA8Kj3VNGmERQVTF_g7UJE/" target="_blank">the Dasopya cheat sheet</a>, which has a quick but rather thorough introduction to the language on a single page, with about 150 words on the back. 
		<br />
		<br />
		We also have our first audio resource for Dasopya, though it's just a short recording on <a href="https://www.dasopya.com/overview" target="_blank">the language overview page</a>. Google Sites doesn't play well with embedded audio, so I'll have to consider either changing websites or using some other workaround like putting them on Youtube instead.
		<br />
		<br />
		There are 2 important art pieces of note that I made since the last update, the first is a commission for my good friend Eijin, which is on <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3l6gxrhhlhc2q" target="_blank">Bluesky</a> and <a href="https://itaku.ee/images/951983" target="_blank">Itaku</a>. The other is SonaPartment #25, which is on <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social/post/3l6qnz6k2x72j" target="_blank">Bluesky</a> and <a href="https://www.deviantart.com/vecderg/art/SonaPartment-25-1111386836" target="_blank">DeviantArt</a>. I'll upload the SonaPartment stuff on Itaku some day, when I'm in the mood to go through the pain of finding and tagging 25 separate comics...
		<br />
		<br />
		Lastly, this is a minor note, but I'm now hosting my old Twitter thread of art tutorials on my website: <a href="https://www.vecderg.com/arttutorials" target="_blank">https://www.vecderg.com/arttutorials</a>
		<br />
		<br />
		This is a list I had for my mouse art tutorial, which I've STILL gotten messages about over the years, so it was important for me to have a stable place for everything to be in. Even if you haven't watched that video, it should be a helpful list of tutorials for anyone to get into art.
		<br />
		<br />
		I know that's a lot, but I really wanted to wait until I was finished with my Peter Rabbit translation before posting this, so do take a peek if you can! I know not many people are interested in learning Dasopya, but Peter Rabbit and its author Beatrix Potter have some absolutely FASCINATING lore (did you know Peter Rabbit was the first licensed character ever?). Just... ignore all the live-action movie stuff.
		<br />
		<br />
		</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts7.html</link>
    <pubDate>
      Sat, Oct 19 2024 03:13:37 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>After Cohost</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
		<p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
		October 3, 2024 - Published 
		</p>

		<img style="width:60%" src="img/cohost.png">

		<p class="normal">
		Cohost is officially read-only, and we've all said our goodbyes. It's still taking a bit of time for me to process everything, but I've already said everything I've wanted to on the subject and feel relatively confident about how I've set up everything, so there's not much more point for me to linger on the subject (on the outside, at least). If you want to read my thoughts, it will be on my Cohost page until the website goes down, and I'm unsure if I have a need to publicly archive it. I did want to save the artpiece here, though.
		<br />
		<br />
		There are a number of other developments. The most major one is that I finished all of RAPTOR's animations for DracoFighter 2! For those keeping count, that leaves 2 characters left for spriting, and 1 whose moveset needs to be finalized. Since spriting is mentally and physically taxing, I will be taking a break for an unknown amount of time, probably about a week. I'm still aiming to finish all the character sprites (barring VFX and minor tweaks) before the end of the year, but DracoFighter's development is still a little bit up in the air, making the goal more of a self-motivation thing than a practical thing.
		</p>

		<img style="width:40%" src="img/raptorwin.gif">

		<p class="normal">
		Dasopya's development has recently been rather slow-going. I have made numerous minor adjustments/additions, but none that are particularly notable. I am hoping to release the cheat sheet soon after some more work. Motivation may be running low, but honestly it might just be due to my number of projects. My interest in learning more languages is increasing again, and I'm also tempted to start even more new projects, as is my eternal issue. Hopefully, my break will help me mentally reset and get back on track. 
		<br />
		<br />
		On a more silly note, I finished a drawing this morning after watching the entirety of Parkour Civilization. Genuinely peak fiction; I can't say enough about how incredible it was to watch on every level. For anyone that knows my sense of humor, I LOVE media that destroys the boundaries between being ironic and genuine, and I hope I remember this for the rest of my life. It's so nonsensical yet unexpectedly well-made, and wonderfully referential -- sometimes self-referential, but mostly just implementing Minecraft knowledge in a way that I love (the raw beef jump is infinitely funnier if you've ever actually done Minecraft parkour).
		<br />
		<br />
		I'm already trying to insert phrases from the movie into my daily speech, personally being a fan of "one block vertical" and "in my entire life, I've never seen this in Parkour Civilization". I will confuse and annoy as many people as possible into watching the entire 2 hours (I did watch Part 2 today and enjoyed it, but I feel it's not super necessary and that the first was better). Anyway, my drawing is a bit larger than I'd like to host here, so you can see it on Itaku: 
		<a href="https://itaku.ee/images/943736" target="_blank">https://itaku.ee/images/943736</a>
		<br />
		<br />
		Other art pieces I finished were <a href="https://itaku.ee/images/939019" target="_blank">a ref sheet for my slug-dragon Doris</a> and <a href="https://itaku.ee/images/937094" target="_blank">a commission for my good buddy TexanSoda.</a> These are Itaku links, but I'm also reposting them on Bluesky. Sorry, putting up every link on every site here just isn't practical!! 
		<br />
		<br />
		I think that's everything important, but as an aside: MAN I wish there were like twice as many hours in a day. There's so much I want to do, but it never feels like there's enough time to do them. I wanna learn like 4 languages, make 3 games on Godot, a few more on PICO-8 and Picotron, finish my stories and articles and my art backlog...
		<br />
		<br />
		</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts6.html</link>
    <pubDate>
      Fri, Oct 04 2024 04:07:40 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>RSS Update</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
		<p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
		September 28, 2024 - Published 
		</p>

		<p class="normal">
		Hi everyone! My local RSS feed should finally be working: <a href="https://vecderg.github.io/feed.xml" target="_blank">https://vecderg.github.io/feed.xml</a>
		<br />
		<br />
		Just in case, <a href="https://vecderg.wordpress.com/feed" target="_blank">the WordPress feed</a> will continue to get the next few posts, but I honestly might continue it indefinitely for the sole reason that it has a built-in comment system. If you run into any issues, feel free to leave a comment there or on my website's front page.
		<br />
		<br />
		If you noticed the warning on the front page, I encountered a weird issue where my website had ads? I haven't been able to replicate it at all, nor anyone I know, so I'll be taking down the warning. I'm sure you all know how to browse safely with adblock, but it's still a bit unsettling since it might've been one of the JS scripts on my front page having some override, though I don't know which one it would be.
		<br />
		<br />
		Stay safe, y'all.
		</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts5.html</link>
    <pubDate>
      Sun, Sep 29 2024 01:42:24 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Conlangs and My Language Journey</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
		<p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
		September 25, 2024 - Published 
		</p>

		<p class="normal">
		One of my mutuals from Cohost recently reached out to me about Globasa, and hey! You're super cool! 
		But it also reminded me that my language journey has been really confusing and worth writing down 
		somewhere. 
		<br />
		<br />
		While I'm not someone unable to make commitments on important things, I'm notoriously fickle 
		when it comes to my hobbies if I'm not lucky enough to hyperfocus on something, so it's understandable. 
		On a more personal note, yes I'm very aware this is like a glaring sign of neurodivergence, 
		and we're still figuring that out.
		<br />
		<br />
		Anyway, my point is: days after I posted 
		<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4pMDnqRRAaM" target="_blank">my Globasa video</a>, 
		I had basically stopped doing anything Globasa. No more interest in studying the grammar, the vocab; 
		no interest in speaking it with people or convincing anyone to learn it. 
		<br />
		<br />
		I was very invested in Globasa's growth, but I lost the energy to partake in it. The same thing happened after I posted the Mini-Linga video. The same thing happened before I even finished the last Ido video. 
		<br />
		<br />
		I did enjoy my time a lot! I just generally have a limited timespan that I'm interested in a particular 
		subject. To be frank, my interest in conlangs has far exceeded this average timespan, possibly because 
		there are so many to choose from. 
		<br />
		<br />
		Since I've essentially only talked about this stuff in-depth on Cohost, I wanted to talk about my WHOLE 
		language journey, largely for my own satisfaction. However, I'll put the most important things upfront first
		for those less interested in me doing a full infodump.
		<br />
		<br />
		--WHAT'S HAPPENING NOW--
		<br />
		<br />
		At this specific second, I'm only committed to 2 languages. I'm committed to learning Japanese, and I'm 
		committed to finishing Dasopya, my conlang. I'm interested in a lot more languages, but these 2 languages alone
		have put enough on my plate that I can't take on much more in good conscience. I'll talk more about Japanese
		later on, but Dasopya is essentially my third attempt at creating an auxiliary language for the whole world to use. 
		<br />
		<br />
		If I include work that's been carried over from the last language, I've been working on this language for 
		almost 3 months straight, so support is much appreciated! You can find the main website 
		<a href="https://www.dasopya.com/" target="_blank">here</a>, which has all the links along with exclusive material.
		<br />
		<br />
		I've done multiple small translations in the language and multiple overviews, but note that the language 
		is still only about 80% finished so there still may be minor changes to the existing vocabulary. I'm 
		aiming for about 800 root words, currently hovering a bit over 700. The grammar is basically 95% complete, 
		where only edge cases are really a cause for concern.
		<br />
		<br />
		If you haven't seen it, Dasopya is a language made to be simple and consistent, with every root word being 2
		syllables or less. Each word is based on sound symbolism and existing languages to sound familiar, but 
		are made unrecognizable to avoid favoring speakers of any region, unlike most auxlangs. Despite the relatively 
		small vocabulary, the grammar and compounding rules allow speakers to express anything they need to.
		<br />
		<br />
		pumi: i songabi tehi sili e legigen!
		<br />
		<br />
		--HOW IT STARTED--
		<br />
		<br />
		It might be a little excessive to talk about this much, but it does give some context for later.
		<br />
		<br />
		In the U.S., most (all?) students are required to take a few years of foreign language. I knew Spanish would be
		the easy choice, but French was a lot more interesting to me. Frankly, this was probably just because Spanish
		would be the common choice for most of my classmates, and I like being an annoying contrarian.
		<br />
		<br />
		Unfortunately, I regretted it pretty quickly because pretty much nothing clicked. This could be for many
		reasons (I vaguely remember not taking the class very seriously), but it's also a not-so-secret fact that
		second language classes in the U.S. aren't super successful. 
		<br />
		<br />
		I distinctly remember struggling with accent marks since I never felt they were explained to me properly (and 
		there's like 4!), so I had to search them up on my own, only to more confusion. While I was lucky enough to 
		enjoy the teacher and the general environment, there was very little I took away from the class by the end of 
		the year, and I switched to Spanish the next year.
		<br />
		<br />
		I remember very little from Spanish class. It felt a lot more like school. Memorize these things, repeat them
		back, do the homework where you repeat it again, then come to class where you get tested on it. 
		<br />
		<br />
		French class may have been where I ate my first croissant and had an (unfulfilled) promise of a cool class 
		trip to France, but Spanish class was entirely fulfilling a requirement. After finishing Spanish class, I had 
		essentially no interest in these languages again.
		<br />
		<br />
		--WHERE IT WENT--
		<br />
		<br />
		From here, most USAmericans never seriously pick up a language again from the statistics I can understand, and
		I don't think that's much of a surprise! School is an easy way to kill enthusiasm in an otherwise interesting
		subject.
		<br />
		<br />
		But for whatever reason, something possessed me to pick up Japanese about a year later, for reasons I won't 
		bother looking for. I've always been a fan of Japanese media, and later most of the culture too, but everyone 
		knew it was a very difficult language to learn. 
		<br />
		<br />
		Either way, about a month later, I gave up not due to the difficulty itself, but because the lack of any 
		speakers to bounce off made it very difficult to practice or keep up motivation.
		<br />
		<br />
		A few years later, having a French-speaking friend, I guess something in me really wanted to pick up
		language studies again, because it still felt like a bit of a whim. I tried French again in a decently valiant 
		attempt -- it lasted over a year, even if on and off -- but I burned out yet again. 
		<br />
		<br />
		This was due to a variety of reasons, but a big sentiment by the end was just frustration. I got very tired of 
		the lack of consistency and constant exceptions. This is the ONLY place I will ever officially say this, but
		this is the ACTUAL reason I began work on Kalibe, later known as Kaliwe. I got annoyed at French!
		<br />
		<br />
		--THE CONLANG ARC--
		<br />
		<br />
		Kaliwe was actually an idea in my head for a long time, from multiple points of inspiration. I found English to
		rather inefficient where many words meant the same thing, and many words could just be derived from existing 
		words by putting them together. I wanted to boil down language to a tiny, simple set of words that could be put
		together in any way you want.
		<br />
		<br />
		Now, I never deluded myself into thinking this was a never-before-done concept, but it's actually only recently
		that I ever found out the actual term for this type of language. Yes, Kaliwe is an a priori oligosynthetic
		auxlang, but the actual logic behind its creation aligns more perfectly with the classification of being a 
		<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Philosophical_language" target="_blank">philosophical language</a>,
		less in the lines of Toki Pona as an example given by Wikipedia, and more in line with a language like 
		<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ro_language" target="_blank">Ro</a>.
		<br />
		<br />
		And if you read the article on Ro, you'll know that philosophical languages never took off, because they just
		dooon't really work in practice! 
		<br />
		<br />
		Anyway, during the creation of Kaliwe, I was talking with a friend who brought up Toki Pona because it was the
		closest equivalent they knew, being a minimalistic conlang. At first I was uninterested, then I realized that
		being rather out of my depth, more points of reference would be helpful. 
		<br />
		<br />
		Eventually, I finished the language and post it online, to a surprising amount of attention. It's not huge, but
		I got many comments. Despite this, I still had no idea what to do WITH the language, other than possibly sneak
		bits of it into my work. Around the same day, I note, "I may learn Toki Pona sometime for similarly nefarious
		purposes." 
		<br />
		<br />
		Huh! Not the reason I expected when I went back to search.
		<br />
		<br />
		--BACK TO LANGUAGE LEARNING--
		<br />
		<br />
		I assume my close proximity with Toki Pona (I'm just gonna keep capitalizing it because I feel like it) was the
		main reason I decided to "bite the bullet" -- I had already learned half the concepts for research purposes, so
		I might as well learn the rest.
		<br />
		<br />
		There were some language-related things that happened during this time (I poked at learning my family's native 
		language, though I'm not sure when I'm spilling what that is), but for the most part, it was just me and my 
		friend learning bits of Toki Pona for months. 
		<br />
		<br />
		I finally had another speaker I could bounce a second language off of! We had resources that were reliable, the
		language was simple, and I couldn't feel self-conscious about my speech, because I wasn't speaking to a native.
		<br />
		<br />
		It was a very good experience, but eventually I wanted more. After bouncing between different conlangs, I came
		to Esperanto.
		<br />
		<br />
		Esperanto was also very simple and easy to learn, but had way more words and angles of expression, so it would
		be more of a project. I spent about 1 month with more intense study than Toki Pona and felt very proud of 
		myself by the end, being able to understand almost 50% of every text I read in that short amount of time. I 
		would still have difficulties remembering words when speaking, but it was an unimaginably different experience 
		from my time with natural languages.
		<br />
		<br />
		By the end of the year, my motivation ran low yet again. A sudden piece of news dropped.
		<br />
		<br />
		--EUROPE--
		<br />
		<br />
		My parents invited me to a trip to Europe! This almost came out of nowhere, and we had to prepare in just a few
		months. As someone several feet deep into languages, I had to figure all that stuff out.
		<br />
		<br />
		After Esperanto, I had already been building up some affection again for the natural languages I had shaken 
		my fist at just less than a year prior, and now was the time to use what I learned. I spent the months to learn
		Italian and German, while giving myself a refresher on Spanish and French. 
		And <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XZi-ChciSIg" target="_blank">the trip went great!</a>
		<br />
		<br />
		(link is for a video on a mostly unrelated subject, but is the only public discussion I have on my trip to Europe)
		<br />
		<br />
		However, after all that I really wanted to settle down and learn a language. For over a year now, I've been 
		The Language Guy to both my friends and family, and more than that, I wanted to prove to myself that I could
		make the commitment to learn a language all the way through.
		<br />
		<br />
		No more auxlangs, no more giving up 1 month in, no more indecision. Let's learn a language!
		<br />
		<br />
		--TO THE PRESENT--
		<br />
		<br />
		Wow, OK this one is getting long. This is the last section, I promise.
		<br />
		<br />
		I chose Spanish, and it fell apart in about a month. It was the "correct" choice, the easy one, the one that I 
		should be able to learn. And, well, I did! I'm not amazing at Spanish, but my goal was be conversational, and
		between my years of schooling, study before the trip, and study after the trip, I was indeed conversational to 
		a very basic degree that could be used with other Spanish speakers, if they spoke slowly enough.
		<br />
		<br />
		But I just couldn't find that secret sauce, the motivation to learn the language that ran deeper than
		"because it's easy and useful." So after everything, I chose Japanese.
		<br />
		<br />
		The majority of my favorite non-USAmerican media is Japanese, I love their food, aesthetics, culture, and
		yes, I do like anime and manga. Call me a weeb if you want! I will only be slightly offended. 
		<br />
		<br />
		My motivation has waned a few times, but we're almost 5 months into Japanese learning, and I think that's a
		great achievement already. After so much time with European languages too, it felt nice to sink my teeth into
		something that was much more foreign, with grammar rules that would take a lot more time for me to learn.
		<br />
		<br />
		However, there was something bothering me in the back of my head. Japanese, it 
		reminded me a lot of conlangs, the way certain words were constructed. Kind of like Kaliwe...
		<br />
		<br />
		I was never fully satisfied with Kaliwe. That's why it's called Kaliwe now, is because I updated Kalibe,
		but I still wasn't happy with this updated version. No, I couldn't make another conlang, it was a bad
		idea!
		<br />
		<br />
		...in a feverish rush around 2AM, I wrote a quick outline document. The next day, I almost worked 13 hours
		straight on Taynmoga.
		<br />
		<br />
		--I LIED--
		<br />
		<br />
		I'm not sure how many people know what it's like to work on something for so long, a hobbyist project,
		without WANTING to. I was essentially compelled by an invisible force. I had to create this. I don't know
		why. Sometimes I feel something similar with art, but this was so much more intense.
		<br />
		<br />
		I work on it for over a week, multiple hours a day for most days. The language has just under 450 words. 
		Another 2 weeks: it breaks 450 words, has a 15 page document, a beginner's guide with 10 lessons. I publish it.
		<br />
		<br />
		Response seems restrained. Then, it's announced that a channel has been added to the Auxlang Discord for it.
		<br />
		<br />
		Oh, fudge.
		<br />
		<br />
		It takes me a while to decide what to do with a language I never really wanted to create? But, eventually I 
		decide that the only thing that made sense was to turn it into something I wanted to support. Abandoning it 
		would feel like my month was wasted, and promoting Taynmoga would feel disingenuous. 
		<br />
		<br />
		And so I made Dasopya. 
		<br />
		<br />
		It has some compromises that make it a bit less "neat" from my ideal concept, but in favor of it being a lot 
		more practical, so I'm happy with it for now. I'm really not sure where it'll go, but I hope it grants me that
		inner peace I've always wanted from creating a conlang I'm satisfied with. 
		<br />
		<br />
		--CONCLUSION--
		<br />
		<br />
		So yeah, basically I learned French, then Spanish, then Japanese, then French again, then made Kaliwe, then
		learned Toki Pona, then had a huge conlang spree where I eventually learned Esperanto, then I learned Spanish
		again, then Italian, then German, then French again, then Spanish again, then Japanese, then I made Taynmoga,
		then I made Dasopya.
		<br />
		<br />
		Make sense? Awesome. I had to skip a few parts.
		<br />
		<br />
		<br />
		<br />
		</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts4.html</link>
    <pubDate>
      Thu, Sep 26 2024 08:09:43 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>
  
 <item>
    <title>On DracoFighter 2</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
		<p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
		September 17, 2024 - Published 
		</p>
      <p class="normal">
		<b>SUMMARY: DracoFighter 2 is in development, has no engine yet but 7/8 of characters have fully designed movesets with 5.5/8 fully sprited. Everything else is still in planning stages.</b>
		<br />
		<br />
		Like a DUMMY I forgot to give an update on my most major project in my last post, but that's 
		OK because this probably deserves its own post anyway. Since this is the only real mention 
		of DracoFighter 2 on this site so far, I'm going to summarize everything from DracoFighter 1 
		to bring everyone up to speed.
		<br />
		<br />
		--ABOUT DRACOFIGHTER 1--
		<br />
		<br />
		DracoFighter is a game I launched on 
		<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2027810/DracoFighter" target="_blank">Steam</a> 
		(and Itch and Google Play Store) marketed as a fighting game for beginners. It's also my 
		dream project, my biggest solo project (game or otherwise), and many other things that I 
		could spend 3 whole articles talking about. 
		<br />
		<br />
		But essentially, it's a 2D fighter meant to <b>bare down the genre to the most essential parts</b>, 
		without resorting to something gimmicky (like Divekick) or dry (like Footsies). Nothing 
		against those games since they deliver perfectly on what they were going for, but they didn't 
		deliver the experience that <i>I</i> was looking for, which was a fully-fledged fighting game 
		that <i>felt</i> like a traditional fighting game, fully playable on mobile devices.
		<br />
		<br />
		DracoFighter is a finished game, but it missed the mark in some areas. It didn't have inputs 
		for up/down to make mobile inputs simpler, but that made jumping/blocking unintuitive for 
		many players. It also had no online play, which killed the possibility of any real widespread 
		playerbase. Since rollback is a necessity nowadays, I would have to rebuild the game in an 
		entirely new engine to make it compatible with rollback. So... why not just do that for a new game?
		<br />
		<br />
		--DRACOFIGHTER 2--
		<br />
		<br />
		Many people were surprised that I was so quick to start a DracoFighter 2, but to be honest, 
		I wanted DracoFighter 2 before Dracofighter 1 even began development. That's because internally, 
		I actually referred to the first game as DracoFighter Zero -- the PREQUEL to the actual game.
		<br />
		<br />
		The original idea for the game had Draco travel to the past with other dragons to fight against 
		the dinosaurs, for reasons I was still developing. However, making my first fighting game have 
		like 8 different characters was very much outside a reasonable scope, so I downsized the cast to 
		4 and wrote the story to happen as an explanation for why he went back in time. This very much 
		worked out in my favor!  
		<br />
		<br />
		DracoFighter 2 is the fully-fledged sequel to DracoFighter 1, planned to have a base cast of 8 characters, longer story, more singleplayer content, and online play with rollback netcode. To make it possible, I'm reusing knowledge/assets from the first game and building on it to feel more like a fully-featured fighting game while still being aimed towards beginners (though I may leave that out of the marketing this time -- I don't think people like buying games that call them a beginner lol).
		<br />
		<br />
		I'm still keeping some features under wraps for announcements later on, but I've mentioned that: 1) there are now only 2 attack buttons (Attack/Special) and 4 directions (U/D/L/R), 2) game mechanics are 90% the same, but a super armor mechanic is being added + jumps are universal and beat grabs, 3) mirroring the 8 base characters, there are 8 secret characters planned, which may be added as free DLC rather than base-game depending on how development goes.
		<br />
		<br />
		HOWEVER, there is a very big, very awkward issue here.<br />
		And that's that I'm spriting a game that doesn't have an engine!
		<br />
		<br />
		--THE ENGINE ISSUE--
		<br />
		<br />
		There is no fighting game engine currently on the market that 1) fits my needs and 2) is complete, so I've been working on what I can while waiting for these engines to be finished. There are a couple of options, but there is a chance that I might have to just make my own from scratch, which isn't ideal for a number of reasons. 
		<br />
		<br />
		We all know networking is hard, especially when you have 0 experience making an online game! But it also comes with other issues that aren't just about making it function -- how do I create a secure system that prevents hackers? If there's a serious bug in the engine, can I be relied upon to fix it? What if I work in Godot, which is an open source engine that can be easily decompiled? If there's a reporting system, who reviews them?
		<br />
		<br />
		Once online is introduced, especially with random players, there are a ton of practical issues where it becomes very unrealistic for a single person to manage everything, especially with no experience. Even the 20 person Discord server for DracoFighter got raided by people who thought it was funny to sling racial slurs, and I couldn't fix it in a timely manner because I was asleep and didn't think it was necessary to appoint any moderators for such a small server...
		<br />
		<br />
		Anyway, my point is that it works a lot better if I work on an engine made by other people who are more experienced that can be reached out to for help, though I may also have to figure out a way sometime to build a team, even if it introduces even more issues (where do I get the money to pay people a full wage!).
		<br />
		<br />
		--ACTUAL UPDATES--
		<br />
		<br />
		Currently, I've been modding new characters into the DracoFighter 1 engine just to test out sprites and movesets, which has been working very well. This build cannot be released due to how buggy it is, but has allowed me to advance a lot of the game despite not having a real engine to build off of. I may release this build as an exclusive thing for DF2 purchasers in the future if people are really interested? Either way, if you see footage of DracoFighter 2 at this point in time, it's probably in this frankenstein of an engine.
		<br />
		<br />
		Speaking of which, here is the first video I uploaded to Bluesky of DracoFighter 2 gameplay:
		<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecdev.bsky.social/post/3l3y6wkjzda2t" target="_blank">https://bsky.app/profile/vecdev.bsky.social/post/3l3y6wkjzda2t</a>
		<br />
		<br />
		As for the confirmed characters:<br />
		Draco, Plexie, BiOS, Cyrus - DracoFighter 1 characters
		<br />
		TREX, RAPTOR, STEGO, DILO - DracoFighter 2 newcomers
		<br />
		<br />
		(They are already named, just won't be announced yet &lt;3)
		<br />
		<br />
		Needs finished moveset design: Cyrus <br />
		Needs considerable number of sprites: RAPTOR (50% finished), DILO (5%), Cyrus (25%)
		<br />
		<br />
		I'm VERY happy with how the currently-finished characters play and animate, and I'm still very excited to show it to the wider world. The reason Cyrus is lagging behind is because unlike the other DracoFighter 1 characters, I've never been fully satisfied with how he played. I'm probably keeping his updates simple, but they still need implementation and testing.
		<br />
		<br />
		Either way, thank you very much for reading! If you want to follow DracoFighter, you can always follow my <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecdev.bsky.social/" target="_blank">Bluesky dev account</a>, 
		but I'll be continuing to note major updates here.
		<br />
		<br />
		</p>

    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts3.html</link>
    <pubDate>
      Wed, Sep 18 2024 20:37:29 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>On Cohost</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
      <p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
		September 12, 2024 - Published 
		</p>

		<p class="normal">
		With Cohost going down, it is essentially the second time I have to move my digital home elsewhere.
		This event is rather big for me, not due to the event alone (which is big, but the website only
		existed for about 2 years and was never colossal), but due to what it signifies for me as someone
		whose home is on the internet.
		<br />
		<br />
		I'm learning how RSS feeds work so this website can be somewhere I connect with more people,
		because it is now one of the few places I can properly express myself. I've written
		<a href="../articles/article1.html">my first article</a> on this website to fully vent out 
		my feelings on the situation, so note that it'll be more negative and dramatic than my usual
		content.
		<br />
		<br />
		Otherwise, the most notable updates are that 1) I'll be more active on BlueSky, where I created
		<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecdev.bsky.social" target="_blank">a new dev account</a> 
		(Vecdev) for anyone only interested in my gamedev endeavors. Of course, you can still
		find me on Bluesky under <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecderg.bsky.social" target="_blank">Vecderg</a> 
		for my general content.
		<br />
		<br />
		2) I've been making great progress on my conlang, <a href="https://www.dasopya.com/" target="_blank">Dasopya</a>!
		I briefly announced this on Cohost, but it's a language made for international communication where
		every word is made from scratch (a priori). I will be continuing to promote and update on it, so 
		expect that in the future -- it currently has over 700 words!
		<br />
		<br />
		The main website is fully laid out to introduce the language, but more interestingly, I also have a 
		converter + font for the alternate writing system! You can find both at this itch page:
		<a href="https://vecderg.itch.io/pyalibu" target="_blank">https://vecderg.itch.io/pyalibu</a>
		<br />
		<br />
		As always, thank you all for the support.
		</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts2.html</link>
    <pubDate>
      Wed, Sep 18 2024 20:36:29 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Archive</title>
    <content:encoded><![CDATA[
      <p class="normal" style="font-size:20px">
		September 12, 2024 - Published 
		</p>

		<p class="normal">
		This is to archive all the old update posts before the RSS Feed was added. These links used to display on the front page,
		but some of them may become broken in the future.
		</p>

		<p class="normal">
		<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vecdev.bsky.social/post/3l3txmtsuiv26" target="_blank">Announcement - New Dev Account! (Bluesky)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://itaku.ee/images/917362" target="_blank">Art - Gulusgammamon Choccy Milk (Itaku)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/7359441-dasopya-the-next-o" target="_blank">Conlang - Dasopya Announcement (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/7262692-sketch-dump" target="_blank">Art - Sketch Dump (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://itaku.ee/posts/139305" target="_blank">Art - Artfight Attacks 3 (Itaku)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://itaku.ee/posts/138038" target="_blank">Art - Artfight Attacks 2 (Itaku)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/6860304-my-new-450-word-lang" target="_blank">Conlang - Taynmoga Announcement (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://itaku.ee/posts/137603" target="_blank">Art - Artfight Attacks 1 (Itaku)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/artphototrad" target="_blank">Article - How to Take Photos of Traditional Art</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/6325949-sona-partment-24-5" target="_blank">Art - SonaPartment #24.5 (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://itaku.ee/images/844803" target="_blank">Art - Ube Sit, Traditional (Itaku)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/6290786-sona-partment-24" target="_blank">Art - SonaPartment #24 (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/6195460-empty" target="_blank">Art - That Dog in Me (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/6153768-sona-partment-23" target="_blank">Art - SonaPartment #23 (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/6069382-sona-partment-22" target="_blank">Art - SonaPartment #22 (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4pMDnqRRAaM" target="_blank">Video - Overview: Globasa Tutorial (Youtube)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/auxlangs3" target="_blank">Article - Thoughts on Auxlang Marketing</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/5986577-sona-partment-21" target="_blank">Art - SonaPartment #21 (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/5892473-sona-partment-20" target="_blank">Art - SonaPartment #20 (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/originalityoverrated" target="_blank">Article - Why Originality is Overrated</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XZi-ChciSIg" target="_blank">Video - 5 Reasons Why Conlangs are NOT Useless (Youtube)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://itaku.ee/images/812476" target="_blank">Art - Polaris Commission (Itaku)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mXBMia_KBkc" target="_blank">Video - Overview: Mini-Linga Tutorial (Youtube)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://itaku.ee/images/783219" target="_blank">Art - Smolder (Itaku)</a><br />
		<br /> 
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/4987553-i-did-the-cassette-t" target="_blank">Art - DracoFighter Casette (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/auxlangs2" target="_blank">Article - Why There Can't be a Perfect Auxlang</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://itaku.ee/images/766686" target="_blank">Art - Hyde Reference Sheet (Itaku)</a><br />
		<br /> 
		<a href="https://itaku.ee/images/753094" target="_blank">Art - Tea Party (Itaku)</a><br />
		<br /> 
		<a href="other.html">Game - Egg Clicker (HTML/JS)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="other.html">Game - Pond's Training (PICO-8)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/artcharacters2" target="_blank">Article - Advanced Character Design</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/4010059-it-is-that-time-of-t" target="_blank">Art - 2023 Art Summary (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br /> 
		<a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1eYUseCDbP1UuJL4Wj1SbsHl1g6_WCFKDUX_wjE-rCkU/edit" target="_blank">Resources - Toki Pona to Kaliwe Document (GDocs, linked from main website)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.vecderg.com/mini/" target="_blank">Resources - Mini-Linga Travel Phrases + Mini Kore Cheat Sheet</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://itaku.ee/images/697572" target="_blank">Art - Meme ft. Gulusgammamon + Gnar (Itaku)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/3841041-he-s-a-big-fan-of-th" target="_blank">Art - Fidget Rave Party (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/artcharacters" target="_blank">Article - Basic Character Design</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/artcolors" target="_blank">Article - Basic Color Theory</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.vecderg.com/kaliwe/" target="_blank">Resources - Kaliwe Reference + Ube Story + Translator</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.vecderg.com/mini/" target="_blank">Resources - Mini-Linga Travel Phrases + Mini Kore Cheat Sheet</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BJ51mFMaAMg" target="_blank">Video - Ido for Beginners pt.4 (Youtube)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://itaku.ee/images/660359" target="_blank">Art - Commission for Premasaur (Itaku)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/3338253-league-of-legends-au" target="_blank">Art - silly League sketch (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.vecderg.com/articles/dracobalance" target="_blank">Article - Game Balance and DracoFighter</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/3239648-meet-the-artist" target="_blank">Art - Meet the Artist (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://cohost.org/Vecderg/post/3143933-sona-partment-19" target="_blank">Art - SonaPartment #19 (Cohost)</a><br />
		<br />
		<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K5xLTMnYEPw" target="_blank">Video - Ido for Beginners pt.3 (Youtube)</a><br />
		<br />
		</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    <link>https://vecderg.github.io/posts/posts1.html</link>
    <pubDate>
      Wed, Sep 18 2024 20:35:29 +0000
    </pubDate>
  </item>
</channel>
</rss>